and dry driving. I'm familiar with
Cleveland, but yeah, I'm not sure
exactly where that is.
My uncle lives in Cleveland, Tennessee,
and we'll be there for this year. It's
in our family reunion.
[Music]
Are you
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Welcome living mana church family. So
happy for you to be here with us on this
Sabbath. So happy that you have decided
to worship with us here at Living Mana
Online Church. We're always excited to
see all of you, each and every one of
you. So please put in the chat where
you're viewing from. And if this is your
first time with us, please put a one in
the chat so we can tell you a little bit
more about our church. But we just want
to say a special welcome to all of you
from all around the world. So just
please put in the chat. That's right. We
are looking forward to a blessed
uh fellowship with you today. Um we have
uh a lot to talk about for our Sabbath
school. We got a couple announcements.
We have a couple of special guests just
for a few um uh moments and then we
we're going to get get into a
uh pretty
uh sensitive Bible school topic today.
Yes. And um which I guess exciting. I
want to say welcome to T. It says T. Tia
maybe. I don't know. T A I don't know. T
but she's a one and Tia or T tell me
where tell us where you are viewing
from. This is your first time with us.
So we want to say a very very special
welcome to you. Thank you for uh
worshiping with us today. I just want
you to know that this is a 100% online
church. We have lots of programming all
throughout the week. We have mental
health Mondays and that we're talk and
that I host I co-host that with Dr.
White. I'm a licensed marriage and
family therapist. He's a psychiatrist
and so we talk about all things mental
health. And then we have True Health
Tuesdays. We have a licensed
nutritionist and two doctors, a
naturopathic doctor and a MD. they host
and they talk about uh lifestyle,
physical lifestyle things that we can do
to live a healthier, better life. We
have prayer all the time, but we have
two prayer services uh on Wednesdays. We
have power Wednesday um that's on altar
live. We have the power line that's on
YouTube and it's live and we pray for
your request right live right in real
time. Um and then um we and we have a
prayer team that's always taking in your
request as well and you'll get more
information about that during the divine
worship hour. Then we have um Thursday
with our young adult pastor Lil Ammy
Richardson. Um and then of course we're
here on Sabbath. So you will have you
have your your choice of of joining us
on any during any of these programs.
You'll find out information during the
divine worship service um on how to sign
up to get text alert and other uh ways
so that you can um just be alerted and
reminded of when we're going live. So
again, welcome. We are happy to have you
here at Living Mana Church. And if we
have any other ones, hopefully that uh
told you what you need to know about
Living Mana Church. All right, you are
in worshiping from Seal, Alabama.
Where is Seal? We're in Huntsville, I
think. is still in in like the south
like deep deep south because we're in
the north like we're at the very top of
the state almost into Tennessee. So I
think you must be way way down. I've
heard of it. I just don't know where
it's located. But welcome. It's very
we're very happy to have you here with
us today. We have Lynette from Mexico.
Welcome. Happy Sabbath to you.
We have Who did I miss?
Okay. Um
I miss Okay. Trinidad. We have Brian
from Trinidad in Tobago. Welcome to
Living Mana Church. Great to see you
here. We have Brother Tennessee. Guess
where he's from, guys. He's from
Tennessee. Good to always see you,
Brother Tennessee. Good to have you
here. Um
yeah. All right. We have
Oh, 30 minutes from Columbus, Georgia. I
got it. Seal, Alabama. That's great. T I
know. I know in the direction of where
you and where you are. It's so great to
have you to have you here. Um and the
mayor family from Dylan, South Carolina.
Good to see you.
Barbara from Anguela, always great to
see you here. Welcome. Happy Sabbath.
And we have uh Leela from North
Carolina. Leela and Wes from North
Carolina. Good to see you here. All
right. We have from Canada. Great.
Welcome.
All right. It's good to see everybody.
Always good to see all of you here on
this Sabbath morning. We want to just
quickly do an announcement. Um Marvin
from Texas, good to see you here.
Welcome. Just a quick announcement with
like what we mentioned last week about
the convocation. The convocation as we
knew it has been cancelled,
but
there is another there's another um
program that we are planning where we
can all still get together and
fellowship, but also be doing service in
the community where we are
fellowshipping. So, we're going to do
we're going to do community service
together and we're going to fellowship
together. That's the best way to
fellowship. So, do we have all of the
details? Not yet. Uh we you know we when
we're going to be giving you that as it
comes together. Um and so just be on the
lookout for that. Be on the lookout for
that because I know so many of you want
to get together and we want to get
together uh with you. Um, but God has
had us pivot to a um a gathering, a
different type of gathering, but still
it's going to be a lot of fun. And we're
going to be doing God's work and we are
going to be uh breaking um or breaking
bread together, hearing his word as
well. So, it's going to be quite the
great fellowship. It'll be the type of
fellowship God wants us to have and
doing work and fellowshipping together
and getting to know each other better.
and how how what better way to get to
know each other but doing uh service for
others for God together and then um also
just spending time together. So we're
excited about that. But just all just a
reminder that the convocation um that
was being planned um is is cancelled but
uh we are planning another another
event. So just just be looking out for
new and more information about that as
we are moving forward. Yeah. So okay.
Well, thank you. Well, I know some of
you are still putting in the chat where
you're viewing from, but welcome once
again to Living Mana Church. You want to
do a t-shirt? Uh, pray, wait, trust God
has a plan. Yes. Um,
well, you know, I have so many shirts
that I was just pulling through and this
one really spoke to me uh today. And I
have another shirt that says God God is
still writing your story. Like stop
taking the pen from him basically like
let him continue to write the story. So,
this one kind of goes with that one.
like you're praying, you're trusting,
God has a plan. Even when um you think
you know what needs to happen, like
don't be in the driver's seat. Like get
in the passenger seat and allow God to
work out the situation in his in his
way. And just I was thinking about it
like just reading this t-shirt. I was I
was thinking about it like you know how
you either some may watch a movie or a
program or something and you don't know
exactly how it's going to end but you're
like sitting back and you're not in
control of it like because you don't
know how it's going to end and you're
being you know you're just like not
knowing. That's how we need to do in
life. It's just like sit back. Sit back,
relax, breathe, trust in God, and just
you're like
watch the movie. Yeah, watch the movie
and watch the movie of your life and
just and watch God work. Your anxiety is
not going to change the movie. Your
worry, which is same thing, fear, which
is all three the same thing, is not
going to change the movie. So stop
wasting your energy and just have peace
and sit back and relax. So
trust God, he has a plan. Yeah. And your
anxiety can actually change the movie.
Let's stay. No, no, no, no. Tell me. I
mean, it can change the movie by you
worrying worrying yourself out of God's
Right. Well, it changes the movie in the
sense that You're not you're not going
to have peace. Like anxiety, worry,
fear, and peace control of the movie,
right? Do not share a space. You're
right. Anxiety and worry and fear can
cause you to mess up the script to try
to jump into the driver's seat and that
messes it up and you don't want to do
that. That's a good point. Thank you.
So, because I wasn't quite sure what you
were going to say, but um yeah, you
don't want to mess it up. And that's
what I tell my children. Like I was just
I was
telling our son that the other a couple
weeks ago that you just you want to be
in the space that God wants you to be
in. So just sit back and whatever doors
open that's God's will. Whatever closes
it's not God's will and you're you're
happy in that space. You're not happy in
the space that you create without God.
You're not happy. Yeah.
Yep. Um,
so
are we ready to bring Yes. our guest our
guest on? I was paying attention to the
chat. Sorry. Yeah. Yes.
So, speaking of uh fellowship,
um we have something that we want to
introduce to our church family. Yes.
This is not just for our church family.
It's for our viewing, you know, viewing
audience. But uh we're going to invite
our guests on and they are Sister Nicole
and Sister Takara. Um please you guys
come on and let's talk about our new
Hangouts
ministry. Yes. Welcome. Welcome ladies.
So good to see you. Hi. Happy Sabbath.
Happy Sabbath. Happy Sabbath to you too.
and Nicole. Nicole, we cannot hear you.
So, I don't know if your mic is muted,
but um I
I heard one of them in my Yeah. Yeah, I
hear Takara, but not not Nicole. Nicole,
I'm testing. Nicole's testing. I can
hear you now. Okay. Yeah, we hear you.
Takara, can you speak?
Takara, can you hear us? Yeah, it's
Takara. We can't hear. We can hear
Nicole. We can't hear you. Takara, but
we can hear Nicole. So, I don't know if
you're muted,
if your mic is on mute, Takara.
Yeah. No, we can't we can't hear you. I
thought I heard you a little bit
earlier, but Okay. Well, maybe um our
tech team, they can work on that. And
Nicole, uh you're gonna have to lead
with it. So, you introduce what's this
new what's this new ministry uh that's
Hangouts and I know to uh Takara is um I
think she's the the the lead hangout
person, but the lead hangouter the lead
hangout person. So, okay. But Nicole,
while we're working on Takara's um being
able to hear her, please let please tell
please tell our audience more about this
new ministry that Living Man Church is
doing.
Absolutely. Well, Pastor Meyers, it kind
of came from your vision. So, um we are
just following um kind of how you laid
it out, but yeah, it's just another
opportunity for us to connect together
as a living family. So, I don't know if
you want to give a little bit of an
overview of what you were thinking. Yep,
I can do that. Uh so, um basically what
we want to do is we just want to provide
a platform. Yeah, we can hear you. We
just want to provide to to we cannot
hear you still. Yeah. Okay. Um so
anyway, we want to provide a platform um
a space for our members to connect and
interact with each other. This is not
Bible study. Um this is literally as we
are uh calling it. These are hangouts.
And so really they're kind of like ice
breakers.
um different type of fun activities for
our members to get to know one another.
Why? Because we're a virtual church,
right? Um and you know, we don't get to
meet each other like we don't get to
fellowship in person. Um so this is
Okay, Takor, they're saying uh that you
do have sound now. So you want to say
something? Can you just say hello?
I don't know. I hear you. Okay, we can.
Can you all hear me? Yes, we can. Praise
the Lord. Yeah. Okay, you can. So,
um, again, so what we're doing is we're
just forming small groups, not based on
Bible study, not based on, you know, you
got to come up with some, you know, deep
theological discussion. We're just, it's
just hanging out. That's literally all
it is. It's very low um low pressure,
low just getting to know people
maintenance. It's just getting to know
people. So, uh if you guys want to jump
in and kind of share some of the some of
the parameters, some of the you know,
just a little bit of detail when we plan
to start things like that. Absolutely.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah, absolutely. Like like
you said, yeah, like you said, pastors
just there's so many ways for us to
connect already with Living Mana, but
this is just going to be another
extension of that. So, we are so excited
to get things kicked off. Just to like
you said, I'm Nicole Dakar is going to
be our lead hangout host and we are two
of the five Hangout support members. So,
I just want to also give uh acknowledge
Jennifer who has done our graphics,
brothers uh Thomas and Spamco who are
also on the support team. So, just want
to say hello to them and thank you for
all your efforts. But yeah, we are super
excited to launch the hangouts ministry
and the first part of the ministry is
going to be those those small groupoup
sessions where like you said there's
zero pressure. We're getting to know
each other. Um we came up with the
tagline of you know we worship together
so let's hang out together. And so
that's really what it's all about. I
love it. Yeah. Yeah. We don't want our
connection to end at the live stream. So
that's right.
We are, like you said, we're going to
focus on guided conversations, ice
breakers, just fostering a space for
connection and growth. So, we we want to
get to know each other. We want to serve
each other. And part of that is just
connecting. So, we want be able to
invite people into our living room
space. So, we're going to focus on
connecting, community, and conversation.
And so we're going to have more
information about the details once we
recruit our hangout hosts, but we're
thinking right now it'll be bi-weekly.
Um, and it'll be a one-hour again zero
pressure type of small group session and
we'll have icebreaker games. Um, but
right now before we launch, we're hoping
to have our first hangout session
churchwide at the end of August,
possibly beginning of September. Um, but
right now we're in the recruitment
phase. So, we people that actually want
to lead these small group sessions and
we're calling them our hangout hosts.
And so, I'll let Takara speak a little
bit more about what is a hangout host,
what's expected, what's not expected.
And I'm gonna let Takar do her thing
now.
Yeah. I was going to say before she
speaks, I just want you guys to know
because I don't know if you can see the
chat, but there's so much excitement in
the chat. Like people are like, I've
been waiting for this. I'm excited about
this. I'm uh Some people are saying I'm
an extrovert. So, this is right up my
alley. I need to meet more people. But
it's for the introverts, too. Don't be
afraid introverts. You don't have to
like somebody said, baby steps for the
introverts. So, still come. You don't
you know when you get when you're
feeling warmed up, you can take your mic
off and show your face. But go ahead,
Takara. Go ahead. Takara is going to ask
what kind of uh what kind of degree or
background do we need for these uh
leaders? Like we you know what
how how skilled
um do we need to be? What kind of
background? This is not just for
anybody. You're learning his sense of
humor right now. Okay. My sense of
humor.
No, we don't need
I know I know Pastor Myers no degree and
I'm so glad that just her sister Tante
is saying that um the excitement in the
chat because that's what we're looking
for. We're looking for people to show
themselves friendly um to be able to
come and you know let your hair down um
and a welcoming environment. This is
nothing about, you know, this isn't
Bible study. This isn't, you don't have
to have a degree. We want friendly
people, welcoming people, warm people
who want to just conversate. Um, as
sister, um, Nicole said earlier, um,
this is community. This is fellowship.
We worship together. Now, let's hang out
together. So this is, you know, if you
were if we were around each other, if we
were together, um, in the same
community, we would invite I would
invite you to come over and hang out.
[Music]
Takara, we're losing you. We see you
talking, but we're not we're not hearing
you. And we want to hear you so bad. So,
let's let Nicole pick up and then
hopefully Takara can can come back. So,
uh she's Oh, you can see why she's
she's the lead home. Yeah, I know. I
know. I know. Yeah, you all can see why
she's the lead. Yeah, I know her
passion. So, she's perfect for that
position. But go but yeah, go ahead,
Nicole. Well, like she was saying, no
degree needed, just a willing spirit.
And think the hangout host can think of
themselves as just inviting people into
their living room. You're not giving a
sermon, you're not giving, you know,
dissertation. You're you're facilitating
conversations and know that we'll have
support. So, we have a uh the Hangout
support team. We are just kind of
putting the plumbing in for this
ministry. Our hangout hosts are really
going to be the heart and soul of the
ministry. And so if you're looking for
opportunities to, you know, learn how to
communicate better or just again foster
fellowship, this is for you. Also, the
introverts like myself who are, it takes
us a while to warm up, you are welcome
also to be a part of the team. You can
help us behind the scenes even with
supporting the Zoom sessions and maybe,
you know, you can step up and co-host
with an established host and then maybe
eventually grow into being a hangout
host. So there's a space for everyone.
So we're excited about it. Yeah. So we
are looking for those who are
interested. Yeah, I'm excited about it
too. And look, let me tell you, the
extroverts are being represented here by
me and the introverts, you have strong
representation by your pastor. So trust
me, you you're okay. You're okay. I was
going to to car. Some people are saying
maybe you should uh try to go out and
come back in. And I don't know if that
will that will make any change, but
don't even worry about it because we're
actually about to to to uh to close this
session, but I do want to say that this
is for everybody, right? Um we want
everybody to be involved in the hangout,
but
we are looking for people that will uh
facilitate. And for those that are
willing to do that, listen, you will not
be responsible for you don't have to
come up with with material. You don't
have to do any of that.
We're going to have a list of ice
breakers and a list of different
activities that can be done. You would
just kind of serve as the host for this
particular small group. And we're not
looking for more than like in each
group, you know, could be anywhere from,
you know, five to eight people. 10 or
less. Yeah. Definitely 10 or less. I
like that. Okay. I like that. So, it's
not one big It's not one big. It's 10 or
less. It's a whole bunch of individual.
I like that. It's going to be
individuals. So, and the hangout hosts,
um, you all will have your own community
and you can share ideas and support one
another. So, you're going to create
community within community as well. So,
we're all here to support because we
really just want everyone to enjoy each
other, you know? I know what it means.
More intimate. Yeah. Yes. Yes. Good. We
can hear you, too. Y can hear me. Yes.
And you might if you want to because
that whole time that you were talking
and we saw your hands moving and you
might want to re say that because we
couldn't hear any of it. We want to hear
what you were saying.
So what I'm saying can you guys hear?
Yes, we can hear you.
Okay. Okay. Go ahead. Go ahead. For some
reason I'm having to switch my mic out.
I know it's what it is. But anyways, as
I was saying when I'm moving my hands
because I talk with my hands. It's like
right now I'm in the living room area
and so I got a t-shirt on. I got some
leggings on and this is just chill. We
don't want anyone to feel any kind of
pressure. Um especially our hangout
host. I'm a hangout host. I'm naturally
social people in my just my friends kind
of like that are, you know, not in the
church really. When I'm hanging out, I'm
kind of like that goofy girl. So I we
want people to be welcoming and um the
hangout host is warm. They're friendly.
Um we you know you're smiling um and
just you know bringing a community
together making it intimate and just
people feeling just warm and
comfortable. It's a it's a cozy
community to come to. We want people to
feel a connection and to be able to um
share whatever is going on in their
heart, whatever they want to share. Um
again I was saying this is not Bible
study. I'm not preaching. Nobody's, you
know, we're we're ministering in a
different way. This is, it still can be
a ministry, but we're ministering in a
way of um community and connection. And
that's what Hangouts is. Come and hang
out in our living rooms. That's where
that's where we're at. Just come and
hang out in our living rooms. Yeah. I I
love it. And people are asking, is it
for members only? And no, it's not. It's
for the whole viewing um audience can
can part. No, this is not for members
only. This is and this is not just for
Seventh Day Adventist either, right?
Of course, your mic wants to This is for
everyone to come to be able to come in
and hang out. Yep. Yep. That is great.
Can we put Okay, that I can tell you
that again. There's a lot of excitement.
There's a lot of excitement. We heard
you, Takara. They heard you. The the the
the the important information. They
heard you from both of you. But the last
very important information, and I know I
saw Gigi put the email, can we put that
back in the chat, um the email where if
they're interested in in helping. Yeah.
And to be one of the hosts, um they can
they can email that email. The email
that it's about to go up. We also we
have a we have a space set up. Oh, go
ahead, pastor. No, I was just going to
say it'll be different times for
different groups. So, it's not like all
you know, it's on this day. every group
will get to kind of kind of choose their
day, choose the time that best suits
them as a group. It's not based on
location. So, um you know, it's Yeah,
it'll be very flexible. Yeah. So, okay,
if you guys see in the chat, yeah, we
are still getting those details and as
it expands and as we grow, we can get an
Yeah. as it expands and grows, we can
get an idea and suggestions from people
coming on from other hangout hosts of
what days and times would be good for
them when they're not busy. So, we want
to be able to work with everyone's
schedule so they can come and hang out.
Yep. This sounds amazing. Absolutely.
So, we actually have a mighty network
space set up already. So, if you are
interested and you're like, "This is
definitely what I want to do," or you
want more information and you're still
unsure, we want you to go to the Hangout
Space and Mighty Networks and there's a
section that says Hangouts 101. Just go
ahead and fill out the interest form
there. That'll help us collect your
email, get information so we can stay in
touch. And we're going to have our first
information meeting on June, Sunday,
June 29th at 700 PM Central time. So
just visit the hangout space or also
email hangouts.urch
if you have any questions in the
meantime. So yeah, absolutely love that.
Um guys, I love the I love their
leadership. I love you guys are you guys
are doing an amazing job. So you can go
to Mighty Networks. There's also an
email um and it was it's in the chat
everyone, but if you see it there, it is
hangoutsmana.urch.
So they can also get in contact with you
there at hangoutsmanana.urch.
Okay. Okay. Takara.
Okay. And but Mighty Networks is a great
place. I told you that's our virtual
church home. So if you you're going to
get information how to join Mighty
Networks if you have not already joined
in the divine worship service, but
you're going to want to join because
this is the type of space where you're
going to get all the type all the
information that you need um outside of
getting text alerts. So that is great.
Send an email if you're inet.
Go ahead. I'm in mighty networks. Anyone
has questions or about, you know, more
information about a hangout host because
that's what we're recruiting for right
now. We're needing Hangouts as myself.
So you'll be joining me and uh if you
have questions, I'm in Mighty Networks.
I'm also on WhatsApp. So anyone can
reach out to me um through Mighty
Networks um through the chat. Um, and
you can also go into the hangouts that's
also on Mighty Networks and reach out to
me there as well. Yeah,
love the ministry, guys. Love the Love
it. This is going to be And there
there's so much excitement and Yeah,
this is great. This is absolutely great.
Yeah. And I think we will we will we
will be including people that do not
speak uh English. So, we'll you know,
we're trying to facilitate as many
people as we can. So, all those details.
We're gonna like a Spanish speaking
hangout of course. Yeah, French. That
would be awesome. Yeah, one of our
support members is in Serbia, so he's
our international liaison. So, we're
definitely going to take it
international. That's right. This is
great. This is great. Thank you guys so
much for coming on. We just want Why
don't we just pray over it so that God
will lead all the the the right host and
and and groups leaders all together.
Yeah. All right, let's pray. Heavenly
Father, thank you, Lord, for this
ministry. Thank you for um just
reminding us, Lord, of the need
uh to to fellowship, to to get to know
each other, Lord. We pray that this
ministry will just um take off, Lord,
and be a powerful
um way to connect, Lord, not only with
our own members, but even those who
maybe not may not be familiar with our
faith. Lord, please bless this ministry,
bless its leaders, Lord, and uh may do a
wonderful work around this globe is our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen. Amen. Amen.
Amen. Amen. Thank you guys. Thank you
again. Thank you. Yes. All right.
Janette saying she's bilingual and Yeah.
Got people excited. They're already
they're you guys are I love to see the
excitement from others. You know, it
wouldn't be Sabbath if you didn't hear
thunder. Not in North North Alabama.
Huntsville. Nope. Tell me it's Sabbath
without telling me it's Sabbath to say
there's thunder outside. I'm like, "Oh,
it's Sabbath." Anyways, seems like we're
all always having storms, but God
protected us last week. He's going to
protect us this week, too. Yeah.
So, praise praise God. All right.
Sabbath school topic. Yeah.
So, there's a lot going on. There's a
lot going on, guys. A lot going on
around the world. And one of our members
um actually it was uh GI that text me
this morning right and was like pastor
pray for me there's a there's a city
down lock down three mile radius
lockdown for a guy who is walking around
with a gun dressed as a police officer.
If any of you have seen the news today,
um two senators,
two state senators, yeah, were killed.
Um
or shot and killed and the husband and
the senator two senators were shot and
killed and then one of their one of them
their spouse was killed as well. Okay.
That's what the article I just I I
thought it was the what the senator and
her husband were killed. Then another
state senator and her husband were shot,
but they went into surgery and they're
still alive. Yeah. So, four people shot
altogether. Two of them deceased. Um and
uh it is uh they believe it's
politically motivated, but GG is safe,
by the way. Twice this morning. She was
right in the area. It was her hotel
um the place she was staying apartment
complex that the the uh this gunman was
kind of hiding out I think in a golf
course behind the hotel is what I think
I heard her say. So he was hiding out in
that area. So there's helicopters all
over and so uh she's she's safe. She's
okay. um we've been in contact with her,
but again, we're just living in some
really crazy really times. Yeah, really
crazy times. We need to pray for the
family of the state senator and her
husband that were that are deceased now.
Pray for them. Pray for the family of
the ones that got shot. Pray for the
whole community. This is very
traumatizing. Yeah. And it and they
believe that it was over a political
issue. Yep. So over immigration. over
immigration and healthare and
healthcare. So, um
yeah, I don't if you I I uh can't
remember the names off the top of my
head now of which senators. Yeah, but if
Yeah, you can. Yeah, but it'll be it'll
it'll be in the news. No, it is in the
news. It is in the news right now as
we're speaking. It's in the news. We uh
they're wars
and these I just want to not not um
go you know government US governor
government government senators but state
senators. So senators um from Minnesota
because people were asking what
senators. So you probably are not
familiar with their names but they are
state Minnesota. Yeah. Senators in
Minnesota. So um
they uh yeah wars, rumors of wars,
protests,
political parades.
Um
there we are.
My daughter called me yesterday. Our
daughter called just thinking she was
like is the world about to the youngest
daughter. She's like is the world about
to end? Is this it that? And um you know
I think the question is is on a lot of
people's minds and there's a lot we
could talk about but we're actually
going to focus in on one particular
thing today. Um and it's huge is you
know these protests in Los Angeles over
immigration.
So we want to we wanted to
deal with this sensitive topic of
immigration from a biblical perspective.
Right? What does the Bible say? What
does the Bible say about
this subject?
So, we're gonna pray and we're going to
jump into this and I'm I'm'll be sharing
some slides on the screen, okay? And
we're just going to walk through this,
right? Um, and we're going to try to
make our decisions based on the word of
God. Uh, you know, how should we
respond? How should we view this? Um,
and again, I know it is a very sensitive
subject. I know that we're treading on
uh sensitive ground here, but I think it
is a subject that we as a church should
be,
you know, we should we should understand
it and we should definitely be seeking
to to
see what the Lord says about this
subject.
So, um let's pray again. Okay. you you
could lead us out in prayer and then
we're gonna jump in and um hit the share
button because we're going to be talking
about this and it's Yeah, it's on
everybody's mind. Yeah, it's on
everybody's mind. Okay. Heavenly Father,
Lord, we we thank you again uh for the
Sabbath. Lord, we just want to lift up
the um those who have that were murdered
uh today, the state senator and her
husband and the other uh state senator
and their spouse, Lord, that were shot.
Lord, we we pray that um they that you
will help them to continue to heal and
pull through this, Lord, and be with
their families, give them peace um
through this difficult time. And Lord,
we just pray that you will be with us,
the Holy Spirit would be with us as we
discuss this topic um of immigration and
what you what um your word has to say,
the principles that are in your word,
Lord. So, I um just lift this up to you
in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
So, this I'm going to say this up front
like this study um is
strictly about what the Bible says and
what we see happening in America uh not
only today but also in the past. Um
should Christians base their decisions?
Some people are putting their
information in the chat as who the
senator was. So, yeah, you you'll see
there in the chat. Should we base and I
believe as Christians we ought to base
everything that we believe on the word
of God. No question. Right. So,
um let's go to the screen and we're
going to be looking at Bible teachings
on immigration and
United States immigration history.
That's what we're going to be looking
at. Those two things. Um and I want to
say this. I want to say this that you
know some people being like okay why are
you talking about this is Sabbath school
this impacts first of all we want to you
know there's people that have a lot of
anxiety right now and are going through
a lot um and you know I'll just be
honest we have a lot of legal
obviously immigrants within the 7th day
Adventist church obviously but and um
our Spanishspeaking churches is there
are this affects it definitely affects
them. There's a lot of people there's a
lot of people here that are seventh day
adventists here that are either might be
starting their papers or you know in the
process of that or whatever but this is
a huge thing um for your brothers and
sisters. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, all
right. So, the first thing we want to do
is what does the Bible say about this
subject of the foreigner
of the migrant? So, let's go to the
screen. Let's go to the screen. And
again, we're dealing with Bible
teachings on immigration and US
immigration policy, right? Um, so we're
going to just we're just going to take
these verses one by one and and just
comment on them. So
in Leviticus 19 33 and 34
uh the Bible says, "And if a stranger
sjourn with thee in your land, you shall
not vex him, but the stranger that
dwelleth with you shall be unto you as
one born among you. You shall love him
as yourself. For you were strangers in
the land of Egypt. I am the Lord your
God." So, let's break that down for for
a moment.
Um, and notice how the text ends. The
text ends, "I am the Lord your God."
Almost like
the reason why you ought to do this is
closely connected with the fact that I
am the Lord your God.
So,
and I want to just see the comments in
the chat. How do you um what does this
verse mean to you?
Um
yeah, what does this church I mean what
does this church what does this verse
mean to you now before you you look at
this verse in the context of
uh well
today is different. Let's just talk
about for a second what it means. What
does Leviticus 19 verse 33 and 34 mean?
How does God expect the the Christian
how did God expect ancient Israel to
treat the stranger?
Another question we would have is did
ancient Israel
have
um immigration laws
in the sense of who gets to come in and
who doesn't? So what do you think? Did
ancient Israel have immigration laws?
Let's go ahead and put that in the chat.
What do you think? Um,
what was God's What was God's position
to
the immigrant? Leviticus 19:33 tells us,
"If a stranger sjourn with you in your
land, you shall not vex him."
So God's command for Israel
was to treat the stranger and vex
meaning you can't
anger anger. Okay. You can't be angry
not be angry with him but anger him like
make him ups make the stranger upset by
treating them unfairly or hurting them
or Okay. Right. All right. Okay. So
everybody go ahead and put a one in the
chat if if you can agree at least in
Leviticus 19:33-34
that
the Christian disposition
to a foreigner in your country should be
one of hospitality
and I think I already know all the yeah
but yeah but and what about what about
what about but and hold on we're going
to get to those right
But according to the Bible thus far,
Leviticus 19:33 and 34, we do see that
uh
yeah, I thought I was missing comments
here. Um,
okay. And and man, I see a lot of uh a
lot of different thoughts and opinions
on what this means. Um, man, I'm so
sorry I missed these comments.
Um, we're not missing as Yeah. Yeah. No,
I just I I wish I would be comment on
them, commenting on them in real time
because now there's so many. But again,
um, so, so the question then is, was
there any biblical limitations on what a
sjourer was? So for example, is a
sjourer one who comes into your country
and plans to stay or were they given a
time limit in which they could stay? So
let's put a one in the chat. One in the
chat if you think like a visa that in
Israel they had a certain time limit
that they could stay and then they had
to leave.
Or uh were there no such laws in Israel?
Two if there were no such laws. one if
the stranger had to leave after a
certain time.
And I think what you're going to see in
this study as we go through this study
is
that there is a difference
in a biblical way to do things and a
difference
to to a secular way to do things. Mhm.
There was no law in Israel, none
whatsoever, that limited the time that a
sjourer could stay in Israel.
So remember, God is the ideal,
right? And the way that he separated
separated Israel uh in the days of their
theocracy, this was this is God saying,
"Here is how I want you to act to to be
character-wise." Mhm. Okay, let's uh
let's go to the next slide. Exodus
22:21.
Uh Exodus 22:21 says, "Thou shalt
neither vex a stranger nor oppress him,
for you were strangers in the land of
Egypt." So again, let's let's come back
again again.
Um,
a the Bible says, "Do not
vex or oppress
a stranger."
Are y'all with me so far? Do not vex or
oppress a stranger. That means according
to the Bible that as long as a stranger
is in your land,
Israel,
do not oppress that stranger. Do not
treat the stranger different than you
would treat one of your own.
Um,
okay. So, do not treat a stranger
different than you would treat your own.
So again, we see here the biblical
mandate for treating
a stranger
is to love the stranger as yourself, to
not oppress or vex or treat in any way
different a stranger than you would
someone else. All right, let's go to
Deuteronomy 10:18 and 19.
uh where the Bible says he doth execute
judgment on the fatherless and the widow
and loveth a stranger in giving him
reignment food and reignment love ye
therefore the stranger actually that's
Deuteronomy 10 love ye therefore the
stranger for you were strangers in the
land of Egypt so again now we are now
told here to love the stranger now
let me ask you a question
um are we called. Let's let's come back
for a moment and here's what I think we
need to to understand here. Love the
stranger
does not correlate with love the sinner.
So in other words,
yeah, love the stranger but hate the
strange. Right? Like okay, I love the
stranger but I hate the strange. That
would be our parallel of saying we love
the sinner. We love the sinner but we
hate the sin. Remember, being a stranger
was not a sin in the Bible. So, y'all
put a one in the chat if you understand
that being a stranger is nowhere defined
in the Bible as a sin. Like, one of the
sins of the Bible is not thou shalt not
be a stranger. All right. So, so again,
put that one in the chat if you
understand
that biblically speaking, being a
stranger
in a strange land was never considered a
sin. Put a one in the chat if you
understand that being a stranger, being
a foreigner in a strange land was never
a sin. Now, if you were common sense,
not a sin. If you were a forced stranger
in a land, then that was a sin because
now you're being taken somewhere against
your will, right? That's a sin.
But for someone to meander into Israel,
to say, "Man, I've heard such good
things about Israel. Israel is I heard
it's the promised land. I heard it's the
land of milk and honey. I want to go."
No one, no individual was ever barred
from going into Israel.
All right, good. I'm glad I'm seeing a
bunch of ones in the chat. And listen,
again, I know this is a very sensitive
subject, especially in times we're
living in now. And and I'm not, you
know, I I I'm simply just following what
the Bible says in this in this thing,
right? Let's just lay out what the Bible
says. Let's compare it to what we're
doing today and let's see does doing
something today make it right just
because we're doing it right.
So now this is not a question of because
the man said it was right. This is not a
question of Republican party versus
Democratic party. This is a question of
America. Mhm. This is a question of
do the laws that we have now reflect
Christian values when it comes to this
particular subject. Okay. So the
question is and I like Lisa's question
because I think it's a very important
one. Yes. Don't immigrants have to
follow the law, right?
Immigrants and citizens need to follow
the law. Mhm. Everybody needs to follow
the law, right? We don't want a a a
country of law breakers, right? So, in a
sense
to separate like, okay,
if an immigrant kills you versus a
citizen killing you,
what is the difference?
There's no difference. There is
literally no difference in an immigrant
killing you versus a citizen killing
you.
The sin was not, oh, an immigrant did it
versus a citizen did it. The sin was the
person killed you. Right? The argument
that people will that use that will say
is, "Well, the illegal immigrant." So,
we're not even we're not even going
there yet. We're we're going to get
there. I asked the question. You said,
"What's the difference?" They'll say,
"They should have been here." That's So,
I'm kind of building this process,
right? I'm kind of building this process
because we're go we're going to look at
the statements of Romans chapter 13, you
know, uh um let every soul be subject,
right, to to the higher powers, speaking
of the government. We're going to deal
with all that, but but we need to not
put the cart before the horse, but
actually deal in a stepbystep process to
see what does the Bible actually
actually
say.
about this subject. So number one, we
see that uh God says love the stranger.
God says don't oppress the stranger. So
in a Christian setting,
it is a sin.
It is a sin
to oppress the stranger, to treat the
stranger differently. Period. End of
story. Bottom line. Now if someone in
our country kills
the first question we ask is not are you
from America or no
right it doesn't matter who you are you
are you should be punished right because
you have broken
a law
so this is why the Bible says in fact
let me see if it's on my next slide
Yeah, let's go here. Let's go back to
the screen.
Notice this. I just want to um
let me read this first. Well, I just
want to remind everyone to um just know
that not only because you're in church,
but just because you're children of God,
that we want to be always respectful
even when we disagree. Right. Okay. And
hopefully nobody's being disrespectful
in the chat. I don't see it. And maybe
you're not reading everything. Go ahead.
Okay. Okay. Okay. All right. So, um,
notice this. One law, Numbers 15:15 and
16. One ordinance shall be both for you
and that of the congregation, and also
for the stranger that with you. One law
and one manner shall be for you and for
the stranger that that sjouneth with
you. So according to the Bible,
you were not to have different laws for
the citizen than you did for the
immigrant. Right? One law for everybody.
You kill, you get punished. You kill,
you get punished. You steal, whether
you're a citizen or a foreigner, you
steal, there's punishment. You lie,
there's punishment, etc. So that makes
sense, right? Everyone put a one in the
chat if that makes sense. So that we
should understand there should be no
difference. Remember now,
this is God's planet.
Yes, this is not our planet. We didn't
make this planet. No, this is God's
planet. And God put people on this
planet.
So when we're looking at this
immigration question, we need to be
looking at it from the pers as a
Christian, we need to be looking at it
from the perspective of God, not from
the perspective of man. Right? This is
God's planet. So now we got to ask a
question. Well, did God set up
uh uh boundaries in which he says do not
cross these boundaries? Because if God
does that, then guess what? It then
becomes a sin to move from one country
to another. See what I'm saying? If God
is like, "Hey, hey, hey, hey, I set up
boundaries."
Then
it would be a sin
for someone who was not an Israelite to
enter into Israel. Does that make sense?
Put a one in the chat if this makes
sense. Now, please don't hesitate to put
a one in the chat because of your end
conclusion, right? We're not getting to
the end conclusion yet. We're simply
trying to say, "Yeah, I can agree with
that. Yeah, I can agree with that. This
is God's planet. We can agree with
that." In God's eyes,
it is not a sin
for a Chinese person, say, to move to
Africa.
Right. Right. It wouldn't be a sin for
two Chinese people to say we want to
live in Africa or 20 or 20,000.
We cannot look at the Bible and say hold
on now that's a sin.
Now under a certain circumstance,
yes,
there comes a there there is a line in
which a country ought to be concerned,
but we're not going there yet. We're
just talking about individuals.
Is it a sin for an individual
to cross boundaries
according to the Bible? No. No. One law
shall be both for the citizen
and for the stranger that sjourns among
you.
Okay.
What about Ezekiel 47
verse 22? It shall come to pass that and
you shall divide it by lot for an
inheritance. Um and this is not Ezekiel
actually. The the verse I'm about to
read next. This is actually from the
book of I think it's the book of
Numbers. Um but it shall come to pass
that you shall divide by lot for an
inheritance unto you and to the
strangers that sjourn among you. This
might be Ezekiel 47 22 and 23. They
shall have inheritance with you among
the tribes of Israel. So again, we see
that God was in favor of strangers
dwelling among the people, right? God
was in favor of strangers dwelling among
his people. There was no
uh there were no laws that required a
check of
well what's your background before you
entered into Israel.
This is the God of the universe. We we
can come back we can come back to the
screen. This is the God of the universe
right? Um
so as we look at the Bible now we see
wait a minute there is no place in
scripture Mhm. in which God commanded
Israel to set up a process whereby they
vetted people who were coming into
Israel.
Now I don't know who's more concerned
about sin
who can more who could be more concerned
about sin than God.
And God in his divine providence
set up no process
whereby the stranger was to be vetted.
That's right. Promo the Exodus included
Egyptians. Yeah. Now, if anybody
deserved to be checked,
if if there was ever if Israel ever had
the right to you an Egyptian,
hold on.
But no such they y'all just tried to
kill us. The only place God is checking
is who's coming back into heaven. That's
right. And there's just that's right,
you know, and he's doing the work to
change the hearts. But I'm just saying
that's the only place that he's not
allowing That's right. whatever is in
heaven. Because the reason because here
we're all in the same boat. We're all
sinners. It doesn't matter where we
live. It doesn't matter whether you're a
citizen of an immigrant can come here
and lose their life because of a
citizen.
I mean, we're all sinners. Absolutely.
And many immigrants did come here and
have their lives taken by citizens.
Right? That was back in back in the
1800s. Definitely immigrants came and
lost their lives at the hands of
citizens. Right? So what I'm saying is
that it happens both ways.
What I'm saying is that according to the
Bible, no distinction was ever to be
made between citizen and foreigner. And
in fact, it was a sin. Let's go back to
Zechariah 7:10. Notice on the screen,
we're commanded to not oppress the
widow, nor the fatherless, nor the
stranger, nor the poor. And let none of
you imagine evil against his brother in
his heart. Uh Matthew 25:35 and 40. For
I was hunger. I was hungered and you
gave me meat. I was a stranger and you
took me in. Okay, let's let's let's
pause for a moment.
So
we cannot go to the Bible to justify
making a difference
between citizen and foreigner.
We can't do that biblically.
Excuse me.
So,
because the Bible nowhere lays out rules
for a nation on here's how I want you to
deal with citizens. There's a pretty
serious issue, right? Where
because a country does something doesn't
mean that it's right. A country has a
right to do something.
Every country has the right to make
their own laws. So now I want you to see
where where I'm going with this, right?
The United States of America and every
other country on the planet has a right
to make their laws,
but the right to make the laws does not
equate with the laws being right.
Y'all put a one in the chat if that
makes sense. Don't think don't think
don't think uh uh immigration laws right
now. I'm simply saying the right to make
a law does not make the law itself
right.
We have plenty of of examples of this.
Um in the days of slavery. So in the
days of slavery
uh the slave owners would let's go back
to the screen.
Romans 13:1, let every soul be subject
unto the p higher powers, for there is
no power of God. Uh there is no power
but of God at uh the powers that be are
ordained of God. Verse two, let's see,
verse two is not on there,
but it basically tells us that we should
obey the government.
The problem is that we can obey the
government as long as it does not go
against the law of God. Then as
Christians, we're called
to rather obey God than man. Does that
make sense?
So
when we when we then look at
the immigration policies of this country
now and I'm not talking about all I'm
just talking about in general because
the immigration policies are pretty
broad. What I'm saying is this.
According to the Bible, we find no
example in scripture of God ever
ordaining
or calling sin calling a sin someone
moving from one country into another.
They were not to be treated different.
They were not to be given a different
set of rules. They were not to be
oppressed. They were not to be looked
down upon. They were not to be Yeah.
They were not to be vexed. They were not
to be demonized. They were not to be
called criminals. They were not to None
of that. All of this All of that is
considered breaking the second greatest
commandment, which is thou shalt love
thy neighbor as thyself.
[Music]
It was never illegal
to go into another country. Mhm. Let me
let me rephrase that. In the Bible, the
Bible never calls it an illegal act to
cross the boundaries of another country.
Never.
Now, a country may have had laws that
said you can't come in. That's different
from it being biblical. It may be a real
law and that country may expect you to
obey that law. And as far as that goes,
that's the law.
All I'm simply saying is because
something is legal doesn't make it
lawful. I'm just taking Jonathan's
words. Because something is legal
doesn't make it biblical. Let me let me
let me Yeah. You tweak that a little
bit. Because something is legal doesn't
make it a biblical position. Mhm.
The idea that someone has committed a
crime against God for entering into the
United States of America to seek a
better life because they're leaving a
place of famine or a place of bloodshed
or a place of war. Think about it in the
context of God. Is God looking down and
going, "Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa. What have you just
done? Mhm. You're trying to get into
another country to get a better life, to
live a better life, to to to provide for
your Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now,
I am not saying that the immigration
laws of America are necessarily
uh unjust, right? We're America's, you
know, we let people in and
they're different, you know, step. You
go through a process. You go through a
process. There's a process. Praise God
that there's a process. That's a very
slow It's a very slow process. However,
it's a very broken process. It's a very
broken process. But what I'm saying is
that in the Bible, there was no process.
There was no process.
Now, brother Tennessee,
not everybody that comes to America is
good. Not everybody in America is good,
but not everybody in America is good
either. If we're trying to keep out sin
or trying to keep out criminals, I mean,
that's one thing that is a process. By
keeping out immigrants, you're not
keeping out criminals. Listen, there's a
lot of people that are afraid to come to
America.
the gun violence. Look at what happens
today. Like people in other countries
like we're the only schools that get
shot up. Only schools that get shot up.
So it's kind of scary to It's not
happening in other countries. Migrate to
America and send your kids to to school
here. Yeah. Because in their countries
that doesn't happen. So sin exists
everywhere.
See what I'm saying, brother Tennessee?
That's right. Sin exists everywhere. If
we think by keeping out the immigrants,
we're keeping out sin.
Whoa. Or by keeping out immigrants,
we're keeping out crime, right?
Whoa. Crime is not dependent upon Crime
is not dependent upon upon where you're
from. Crime is a matter of the human
heart.
Crime is not something that crosses
political crosses national boundaries.
Crime is something that is found in the
heart and immigration laws are not going
to stop the contents of the heart.
Right?
Are y'all following me so far? So again,
I'm just arguing from a biblical
perspective.
And you know, yeah, when you argue from
the Bible, you could always be wrong. If
someone says, "Hey, pastor, here's a
study that proves that God is for uh
immigration laws where you check people
before they come into your country
because you want to see what their past
was." Man, can you imagine if heaven was
based on that principle? I want to see
what your past what your past is. He
knows. Yeah. Now, he knows our past.
Remember and he knows when we remember
when we decided to go for Jesus and
That's right. Erase, erase our path.
Israelites should have been all over the
Egyptians. Israelites should have been
eyeing the Egyptians. They should have
been like, "You can't come with us. You
can't come with us. Look what you just
did. You had us enslaved and now we're
free and now and you want to come with
us." I mean, that would have been the
natural human exactly nature response.
But watch this, y'all. God set a or I
don't want you around my children.
You're not saved. God set, think about
this. Some of those very slave owners
had beat their children,
had beaten them. Mercy.
And then God says he puts a protective
barrier around the Egyptians
that were like, "Hey, we're coming with
you."
Because they saw what h they saw the
plagues and they saw God, you know,
that's right. Make a way. And it doesn't
mean that they were all converted. No,
I'm not saying they were converted, but
they were like, h of course maybe I
should go with you, right? But it
doesn't mean that they were all
converted, right? They could they they
could have easily come in and committed
crimes. But guess what? If you come into
the country and you commit crimes and
break break the laws of Israel, whether
you're a a citizen or a stranger, you
are getting punished the same way. It
wasn't a different degree of punishment
for the stranger than it was for Israel.
Mhm. So
when the Bible says obey the laws of God
or obey the laws of the government,
remember there's a caveat to that.
It's not just whatever the government
says is right is is is the Christian
thing to do.
No, not at all.
When the when the government makes a law
that is contrary to the Christian values
of love your neighbor as yourself,
then I'm not saying to go out and
necessarily necessarily protest the law,
but you can at least in your mind say,
"Hey, it's the law of the land, but as a
Christian, I have to disagree because
biblically I cannot
justify
making a difference between the citizen
between the citizen and the immigrant.
This is God's land. This is God's earth,
not mine. Okay? Now, now hold your
thought here because there they're
they're important questions that rise
because of this. Let's go to Acts 17:26.
And I think we're we're going to get to
the questions most people have on their
minds, right? What about the elite? What
about the crime? And what about this and
what about that? Hold on. So, Acts 17
verse 26. Were you gonna say something?
No, I'm just thinking. Okay. Citizens
commit crime every day. Exact. Citizens
commit crimes every day.
So the Bible says in Acts 17:26, "God
has made of one blood all nations of men
and has determined the times before
appointed and the bounds of their
habitation." And some people have used
this verse, some people have used this
verse to say that God sets up
boundaries. But if that is true, God
sets up boundaries. Yes. But listen
y'all.
If the verse is being used to say what
people try to make it say, then it would
be a sin to cross those boundaries. It
would be a sin for someone to eur from
Europe to come to America. It would be a
sin for someone from America to go to
London, for someone from America to go
to Africa. And God has no such
boundaries. So if God has no such
boundaries, who are we to put such
boundaries in place? Because we want to
keep our crime. God says, "Look, the
crime is in your heart. It's not a So,
yes, you're absolutely correct. But I
don't think our immigration laws have
been set up because of crime. But we're
gonna get to that. Okay, let's go back
to the screen. Let's go back to the
screen and and I want you to check this
out, right? So, God did have boundaries
for Israel. There were walls set up and
there is a reason why. Yes, there God
Israel was to protect itself
from what?
Let's pause for a second. Just take this
down for a second. What was Israel to
protect themselves from?
I'm going to use a word and it begins
with the word I. I'm going see if you
guys can guess it. What What did God
expect Israel to? What did God say?
Israel, I will protect you from this.
begins with a with the word I and it's a
military word. It's a military word.
So it's when not one
Chinese person or African person or you
know Mexican, not one, not 10,
not 20,000,
but an entire army of another nation
wants to what?
I
next word is N. Next, what's the word?
Next letter is N. In
invasion.
Invasion. Invade. Very good.
Governments have the right to protect
themselves from invasion. That's a
different story. Listen to me now.
Immigration
is a very different thing from invasion.
So let me see if some put a one in the
chat if you would if you would agree
that immigration and invasion are two
different things in the true sense of
the meaning of invasion and like in war.
Yes, invasion and immigrant immigration
are two different things but the way
some have tried we're getting there.
We're getting there. What is an
invasion?
An invasion
is a military attack on another nation.
Did were there countries that attempted
to invade Israel?
Absolutely. Y'all yes.
And and when a nation is being invaded,
do they have a right to protect
themselves?
Absolutely beloved. An invasion is a
military event.
So what do you see the problem here is?
What do you see the problem is here?
Immigration
is not an invasion.
To use the word invasion
to apply to immigrants is by nature to
demonize immigrants and to oppress them
and to vex them.
Every immigrant every immigrant that
enters this country illegal is a sinner.
Every immigrant that enters this country
today legally is a sinner,
could be drug dealing,
maybe a drinker,
maybe a murderer,
just as every citizen in this country is
a sinner,
could be a drug dealer, could be a
murderer.
M
geographical boundaries
do nothing to address the problem of
sin.
So what I'm saying is when we take the
term invasion and apply it to immigrants
seeking to find a better life are are
there sinners asylum safety asylum say
are there immigrants
that are sinners that are entering into
this country? Mhm. Every last one of
them is a sinner.
Are there immigrants?
Are there citizens in this country that
are criminals?
Yes. Are there are there citizens in
this country that are sinners? Every one
of them. Mhm. The problem that The
problem that I see is that when we see
immigrants coming into this country as
an invasion, we're now employing
military terms, which means, yeah, those
Mexicans are dangerous.
Most of them are dangerous. Maybe not
all of them, but many of them are
dangerous. particularly more dangerous
than us Americans because we're American
and they're not of us. They are not like
us.
I just want to say um this is and now
now we're going to come I'm sorry I'm
cutting you off but now we're going to
come to the heat of the study.
So y'all better be ready for this. I'm
gonna go back to the screen but go
ahead. So, I was just going to say what
you what you just said like so from my
personal experience living in growing up
in a border state to Mexico and
California.
Um,
I grew up all around. I mean, legal
immigrants and I know illegal immigrants
as well. Um, couldn't have felt safer.
Couldn't have felt safer.
Kind,
hardworking.
um helpful when you need a helping hand
um type of people. I mean just the
culture Yeah. the uh strong family um
structure and base that they they have
because I mean it's very strong. Yeah.
Um
amazing food.
But no, but with the safety thing um I
never I just want to say this. I just I
never ever
felt unsafe. Yeah. Um I mean it's not
saying like every single person was not,
you know, had never done bad things, but
the majority that's not the case. And I
just think that because there's um a
picture that has been painted
that that is so many of illegal
immigrants coming from Yeah. um our
southern border. Pause. That's just not
the case. But go ahead. It's spiritual.
I see your question and I'm coming to
that next that very thing next. So So I
see it and I'm I'mma address that. Okay.
Go ahead. Well, I just had to say that
um I just I never experienced that. So
and here's the thing, you guys.
As far as the Bible is concerned, there
is no such thing as an illegal alien.
The only illegal aliens in the Bible
were invading armies.
Otherwise, that part right there,
Carrie, go ahead. Yeah, there is no such
thing in the Bible as an illegal alien.
You don't belong here. Wait, you're in
Israel? Wait, who? You're an Egyptian?
There is no such thing as an illegal
alien.
Now,
in a United States context, yes, there
is such a thing as an illegal alien. But
the United States definition of an
illegal alien and any other country you
want to use that has these same laws is
not a biblical definition.
So what I'm saying is you may agree, you
may feel better with, you know, the laws
regarding illegal alien, but all I want
you to understand is that according to
the Bible, there is no such thing as an
illegal alien. The only illegal aliens
in the Bible were invading armies.
Armies that were trying to invade
Israel, destroy Israel. And then and
then in that context
any army trying to invade another
country
that is what was considered illegal. Now
again you might say I agree with
American policy
but you can't agree with it on biblical
grounds
because there is no biblical ground
to agree with
there. There's no Bible-based argument.
Now, now it's time to check the history.
So, if you know if and if you look at
ancient Rome, you look at you know uh
ancient Babylon, you look at there were
never any laws to my knowledge, to my
understanding, there might have been
certain laws that were laws in general,
but there was never an where's your visa
papers,
right? Where? Where's your Where's your
passport?
There were open border policies. And
here's the interesting thing.
America
once had open border policies. Y'all put
a one in the chat if you knew that.
America once had open border uh
policies.
Put a one in the chat if you knew that.
There was a time
the laws that we have in place now were
not always part of American history.
So
in the 1700s,
in the 1800s,
and really up to about the 18 up to
about 1880,
there were no
laws prohibiting people. Now, why do you
think, so I'm seeing the ones in the
chat, and I'm going to ask a question.
Why do you think there were no
border policies in America before
the 1880s?
While they're while you're while they're
thinking, I just want to say because
somebody's comment made me think of
this, like we're all illegal immigrants
when it comes to heaven. That's right.
But God extended grace. That's right.
Okay, that's all I had to say. That's
right.
That's right. We all des we all deserve
no no entrance. Yep. Yep. Cuz we're all
criminals. Cuz we're all criminals. We
are all criminals. All And he extended
He gave his life extended grace. Yeah.
And forgave us. Yeah. Yeah. So, and
changed us, of course, but we get to
come in.
So, okay.
So, again,
um Gigi, we just read that Romans 13:1,
uh be subject to the government. Um we
read that and understood that that there
is context to that when the government
says we want to pass a Sunday law we
will trust me people will not be walking
Adventists will not be walking around
saying Romans 13:1 and2 right obey the
government no
there's a certain place a certain point
where when the laws of the land
force you
to embibe in the spirit that is against
God's commandments whether that is
loving God with all your heart or loving
your neighbor as yourself. Listen y'all,
this is a very serious thing because if
if you are treating the the the stranger
as somehow inherently criminal,
you are breaking the second commandment
which says, "Thou shalt love thy
neighbor as thyself." You're breaking
the commandment that says, "Do not treat
the stranger, the foreigner,
as some do not vex or oppress the
foreigner." now
or treat them like they're beneath you.
According to the Bible, there's no such
thing as an illegal immigrant, an
illegal sjourer, an illegal foreigner.
In fact, when Jesus comes back, he's
going to say, "In as much as you did
this unto the least of these, my
brethren," he's talking about the
strangers. Now,
the question is, why were there no
immigration laws in the 1800s?
We had people coming into America, but
who were they?
Who were the people coming into America?
Y'all go ahead and put it in the chat.
In the 1800s, everybody in America
are immigrants.
That's right. Or from somewhere else.
Yeah. So, who were the people that were
coming into America in the 1860s, in the
1840s, in the 1830s, in the 1820s?
Who are they?
Where were they coming from? Let me ask
that question. Where were the foreigners
coming from?
Now, don't include Africa, okay? Because
there were no Africans coming here of
their own free will, right? The only
black people, the only Africans that
were here were taken by force, right?
There are no immigration, there are no
immigration laws needed for that. But
they were Europeans. Europeans, right?
So Europeans were coming into the land
freely. Freely. No question on on on
immigration. Nothing. And why were they
coming? Yeah. They were coming to escape
tyranny. Yeah. They so they could
worship God the way they wanted or just
have a better life than better life.
Better life than what they were. Better
life. Mercy. Then
something happened. Uh let's go. Let's
go to the screen.
Uh, anybody ever heard of the yellow
peril?
The yellow peril?
So, the yellow per the yellow peril and
the Chinese exclusion act of 1882. The
yellow peril, also the also known as the
yellow terror, the yellow menace, and
the yellow spectre, is a racist color
metaphor that depicts the people of East
and Southern and Southeast Asia as an
existential danger to the Western world.
And so the Chinese Exclusion Act of 1882
was passed. This was the first major
federal restriction on immigration and
it explicit explicitly banned an ethnic
group
and had to execute certain treaty
stipulations relating to Chinese. So
let's come back for a moment.
Immigration laws
did not start until when?
What was the what was the reason behind
the first immigration law in America?
to so to stop the
Chinese and to stop. So remember the
yellow peril, if you never heard of it,
the yellow peril was basically this fear
of who are these Chinese people? They're
they're lower than us. Um they are they
are beneath us, but they're coming to
America in droves. Wait a minute.
They are
invading.
What are they doing? They're going to
try to invade
the country.
Take over. Replace. Yes. Invade.
So Indie said criminals have been
Patrice said Indies. No. Criminals have
been coming to America since 19 since
1492.
Listen to me y'all.
That needs to be a t-shirt. That is a
t-shirt. That is a t-shirt. Patrice,
make the t-shirt.
That's a t-shirt. Part of her clothing
line.
In this country, we have laws to deal
with criminals. And any person in this
country should be subject to those laws.
You steal, we don't care where you from,
you're going to jail, right? You lie,
you bear false witness, you kill.
Whatever the issue is in this country,
we're a country of laws. In this
country, if you do this, this, and this,
you're going to jail. You're going to be
punished for it. Bottom line.
That's as far as we can agree politic
biblically. Now, if you want to agree
politically, then go ahead and agree
politically, but don't say that it's
Bible. No. Right. That's all I'm saying.
You may agree, you may say, "Yeah, we
need these laws, but we didn't need them
in the 1860s, in the 1850s." But once
people of different color started coming
into the country freely, this is the
history behind immigration,
immigration laws in America.
It all
it all leads back to the same thing.
Meaning like this is somebody's comment
in the chat. It said the Europeans came
and they actually killed the n the
native people and took over. They did
exactly
that was an invasion. They Yes. They did
exactly what they're afraid
of others are going to do to them. Yeah.
And listen y'all, this is not we're not
talking everybody, right? We're not
talking, oh this is everybody. We're
just saying historically speaking, it's
history. History. This is what happened.
And so now, and listen, immigration laws
is not a political party thing. No, both
political parties have backed
immigration laws. And I think it's they
do it so now because it's just such a
part of American society, right? Oh, you
got to have immigration laws. That's
common sense. However, it may be common
sense, but it's not
biblical sense.
It's not biblical
to determine, oh well, you get to come
in and you don't you don't get to come
in. Now listen, if there's a criminal
that's if you know that someone's coming
in to do harm to the country, you have
every right to say, yeah, no, no, no,
no. We're not letting you in this
country. And that should be on a person
byperson basis. M but just the blanket
um
treatment
regarding
those who are seeking refuge in this
country.
You cannot say it is biblical. What I'm
and and what's happening right now I
mean obviously you guys all watch the
news so you see what's happening right
now. That is nothing compared to um
yes there were immigration laws on the
books um they were not being enforced in
this way. This is um inhumane way that
it's being forced enforced. Right.
Right. So I mean so it's no comparison
to what was on the books. I mean whether
it's you know
politicians in general I mean there's
immigration laws so it's whether
Democrat or Republican there's laws but
yeah it's a different discussion of
what's happening today what's happening
right now it's completely completely
different and in the past in the past if
you what we're saying if you broke the
law if you were here illegally and you
broke the law then you are deported
immediately
if you've in the past. If you've come
here illegally and you have been um a
good citizen, you're paying your taxes,
you're working, you have a job, you are
you are contributing to this country.
Yeah. Then they made a way for you to
become a legal citizen. Yeah. That just
makes common and humanitarian sense.
Yeah. And it matches more with the
Bible. So now again, I'm not even
dealing with what's happening today.
That's that's not what I'm dealing with
at all. But that's where our minds are.
That's where our minds are and that's
why we're talking about this, right? But
what I'm saying is if we just put it
aside because some people say, "Oh,
well, it's political. If the Democrats
do it, then no." I'm saying that as a
whole, we need to understand why
immigration laws became a reality in
America. So it started in 1882 with the
Chinese Exclusion Act. That was the
first one. And now I want you to see
this. Let's go back to the screen. 1924.
1924, the National Origins Act of 1924,
which cottified basically white
supremacy. Basically, the immigration
act of 1924 instituted racial quotas
that drastically limited immigration
from non European nations. This was
based on eugenics and the belief that
some races were were more assimilable.
Um, it favored the northern and western
European countries and banned almost all
Asians except Filipinos due to US
colonial control. Uh, America must be
kept American.
This law made immigration a tool of
racial and c cultural engineering. So,
here's what I'm saying you guys.
It started
with keep the Chinese out because they
were the first ones that were trying to,
you know, get, hey, we want to come to
America, too.
But by 1924, now when other uh um we can
take that off the screen. We can take it
off the screen.
When other nationalities
and people are now trying to come to
America now, in order to preserve
the the makeup of what America was,
immigration laws were upped. Now listen
you guys.
It it's important for us to understand
that
we live in a sinful world. And I know we
you know
we we like to idealize
America.
America has its good, but it also has
its bad.
And we cannot close our eyes to the bad
just because the good is good. And
listen, the good is good. Nobody's
saying the good is not good. But as a
Christian, when you're navigating these
kinds of issues, you have to be careful
to think biblically because when you end
up getting on a bandwagon of, yeah, this
is why I believe this. You may not even
realize that you are fighting against
the spirit of God
because what you think is a good law is
actually putting within you a spirit of
judgment
against people
who are not of your ilk, who are not of
your tribe, who are not of your color,
who are not of your nation. Yeah. Yeah.
We're better than them. We are. Yeah,
they're illegal. What makes them illegal
just because they desire to live
a better life for themselves
and their children? What makes them
criminals? What makes them illegal? What
makes them
so a people to be feared
because they recognize the
opportunities?
Why should they why should they wait 10
years to get an opportunity to live a
better life?
Again, do I have all the answers? No.
Um, but you're just laying out biblical
principles. I'm just laying out biblical
principles. So, pastor, what are you
saying we do as a nation? I don't know.
I don't I don't have the answer. I I
think that Yeah. you know when people
are coming into your country uh when
people are coming into the country you
you want to of it's natural to want to
make sure that someone is not coming in
with ill intent
but how do you judge the human heart
how do you judge a sleeper who says hey
you know what I've been training for 20
years to come into your country and blow
stuff up but I have an impeccable record
in my country you can't spot that
We know when a country is trying to
invade us, but don't put upon an
immigrant population
the the title of invader or invasion
because you are vexing the strangers
who are looking
to live a better life.
I think yeah I mean if they're saying
like pastor what do we do? Well, this is
me speaking, but they say, "What do we
what are we supposed to do?" I think
number one, I think it would be
so healthy for America, really, for our
political leaders and for American
citizens, for us, as you took a um a
journey backwards into history. Um
because our biggest um issue in life
that causes problems is that we forget,
right? Be a student of history.
um and understand that
this country was founded
by
um I don't know if I want to call them
illegal immigrants, but they did did
illegal things when they got here
because there was already somebody here.
So, and they, you know, they invaded and
took over uh over the land. And so what
I'm saying is
the way you I say you the way America
was started the way you it was
established and came and and started and
and people came here. Um I mean there
were already Native Americans here. Um
but what you again I'm going to say this
again what you are afraid of is what has
already been done. Yeah. And then now
that
a group of people did that Now, um you
don't want to allow other people to be
able to flee something that is um
obviously not a good life, right? I
mean, I just want to I just want to
really keep it and I pause for a second.
Hold your thought. Okay. Uh Peterson
asks, "What about lootings, gangs,
murder, and vandalism is not seeking
refuge? How do we reconcile that?" And
listen, I I agree. But here's what I'm
saying, Peterson, is that looting,
gangs, murder, and vandalism is not an
immigration thing. It's not. Those who
are looting and No, no, no, no, no. Hold
on. I mean, I'm saying before we even
talk about those who are looting,
there's citizens that are looting. I'm
not say I'm saying that looting is a
crime. Being in a gang is a crime. Those
are citizens. Murder is a crime.
Vandalism is a crime. So we shouldn't
look at those things as well is a
citizen doing it or is a uh an illegal
immigrant an illegal immigrant. No is a
person doing this that person needs to
be arrested. So when we stop thinking
Peterson does that make sense? When we
stop thinking in the in the sense of are
they one of us doing this or are we
allowed to do this but they not? No.
Nobody's allowed to loot, be in a gang,
murder or vandalize. And that is not a
particularly migrant thing to do, right?
That is a human thing. So that's why
when the Bible says there should be
there should be one law for the stranger
and for him that and for the the the
citizen,
this this is exactly what we're saying.
And I would like to say we don't say
he's a murderer because he's a he's a
migrant. He's a murderer because he's a
murderer. And because they speak in
blanket terms, this is what you see on
the media. This is what you see on the
media in and in in some circles. They
speak in blank blanket terms. Um like
you know they are they're they're raping
our women. They're uh committing crimes.
All of that they so this is the military
now. This is an organized group of
people that are actually seeking to
invade. And that is the and that's not
even factual. Those numbers are not
there. Those numbers don't exist. I mean
does that happen on um you know in small
much much much smaller numbers yes um
but there's
the numbers are are greater or higher
with citizens doing those crimes
when I can tell you I mean which is why
I go back to saying the question is not
about was it a citizen but I'm talking
about the rape and the molestation those
are family members that are citizens and
not all family members but the majority
are family members that that are
citizens that are harming our young
women and our little boys too. And
here's what I'm saying. This is a human
problem. It is not an immigrant problem,
right? It is not a citizen problem. It
is a human problem. So when we start to
say the immigrants are looting and the
we're what we're saying is the
immigrants are animals and we are we are
civilized people. The immigrants and the
countries they come from are animals and
we are civilized people. And this is why
God says no, do not oppress the do not
vex the immigrant. And this is what I
think our society is leading people
in to inherit this disposition of we are
better than you because we're American
and you're from those, you know, those
bad countries, those countries that
those countries that where they do these
things. You are you are an animal when
you think you're betterized. Exactly.
When you think you're better than
another group of people, those are
racist thoughts. That's that's creating
racist thoughts. We are not better as
Americans than than other people. We
have that same bad behavior right here
in our country. And we have it and large
we have it at larger numbers than what
foreigners come in and do to us. We do
much worse to ourselves. Yeah.
Yeah. So, so here's the thing.
When you understand that our immigration
laws, let me let me let me
Yeah, there is
there is so much here. Um,
yeah. Let let's go to this screen real
quick just so that you see that I'm not
saying this is a political like a
political party thing, right? 1986,
Reagan signs the Immigration Reform and
Control Act grants amnesty to 3 million
undocumented immigrants, but
criminalizes employers for hiring them.
In 1996, Bill Clinton signs uh I r iir
expanding deportation powers, mandating
mandatory detentions in 2001
to present. Um um policies have framed
immigration as a national security issue
and it goes on, right? So this is not oh
it's the Republicans doing this or this
is an American thing, right? And I think
Obama um deported
more more than I know he did yeah more
than Trump did in his first but it was
according to probably more than any
other any other president but that was
of he was giving well according to the
numbers that they were illegal they no
I'm sorry they were illegal immigrants
but they had committed crimes they were
they had committed crimes while they
were here and they really started to
clean house at that but that's what the
numbers say. So what I'm saying is that
this is both this is an American thing,
right? It's not Republican versus
Democrat. It is the fact that this is a
policy that began in America on racist
grounds, but now it's become such part
of the fabric that we just take it as
normal. Yeah, everybody knows this,
right?
As Christians,
we need to go back and say, "Hey, is
this is this framework isn't even is
this framework even biblical?
Is it biblical to say someone is an
illegal? Is it show me an illegal
immigrant in the Bible?
Show me the problem of illegal
immigration in the Bible.
In fact,
when you look at Israel's history, when
Jesus came, man, they were like, "Get
the Romans out of our of our place."
Yeah, they were occupying.
But that spirit of we don't like others
who are not like us, that was even in
Israel.
And I believe it's in the church, the
the Protestant church today as a whole.
Yeah, it's there.
It's there. So,
um
the idea of preserving America because
of a fear. And listen to me y'all. If
you don't believe what I'm saying now,
go and Google go and Google the
replacement
uh the great replacement.
M just go Google the great replacement
to see what that is.
The great replacement is an is this idea
that there is a plot out to replace
Americans and a certain type of
Americans by bringing in all the
immigrants. This is a calculated plot.
It's it's the same thing they said about
the Chinese when they were coming into
the country in the in the 1880s. So they
made the im the the Chinese act of 1882.
This is not new
and belove I believe that a lot that
that had its origin
in the mind of Satan.
How can I get people to hate each other?
How can I get people?
How can I get people
to think that they are better than they
are better than the others? And you're
coming and this is history. I'm not
making this history up. This is history.
Immigration laws in this country were
designed to keep out non-Europeans.
Period.
So, I don't think it's the same. It's
exactly the same today. That's not what
I'm saying. But I need you to take in
context the origin of why America has a
system. And the origin is not good. And
I think to a large degree
there is a lot of that spirit still
alive in what's going on today.
I would high yes a lot a lot of that
spirit because of that spirit I mean
is what's going on today is ICE invading
the northern border
no
just the southern and places where I
mean yeah so to say that there to
believe that an invasion is happening in
this country
is the most
on this basis is the most
unbiblical
position that a Christian could take
regarding this. An invasion is a
military conquest. Immigrants are not to
be treated as enemies.
Immigrant versus invasion are two two
different things different things. Mhm.
And if you have a mass of people trying
to get into a country to live a better
life that is not an invasion, not in
God's eyes.
No such thing in the Bible as an illegal
immigrant. Now again, let me close with
this.
If you want to politically agree on this
policy, that is your right.
All I'm saying is don't say that that's
based on the Bible. Right? That's all.
And in fact,
you should recognize that is that it is
diametrically opposed to the Bible, but
you still have the right to believe it.
But just don't think that you're doing
the Christian thing or you're believing
the Christian thing because a lot of
Christians back this. Don't think that.
Um, all right. Yeah, we're definitely
over time today, guys, but it's quite
the topic and I think a good history
lesson or refresher and reminder for
for some um and so yeah, that was a very
good very good study. Thank you. Yeah.
And uh we are so thankful to all of you
for for being here and participating.
Please share on your social media.
Invite your friends and family to church
today because we're just getting
started. Even though we went over some,
but we're still just getting started. Do
you want to let them know what your
topic is today? I will, but I I you know
what it's I see so many questions in the
chat. So many good questions, so many
good comments, and so many honest
questions. You know what? You know, I
don't see anybody here like hating.
Right. Right. Right. No. And I think
it's good. That's I see people having
genuine questions and that's this is
what I'm gonna tell them to do. Bring
that to the afterlow.
Well, you'll be there so you can answer.
I'm just saying if you try to answer all
those questions, we gonna be here
forever. There won't be no sermon today.
Uh but we do have boundaries here. Yeah.
We really don't with our time, but we
try to So, let me let me let me let this
be the last thing. Okay. Any act of
vandalism
done in any set of pro in any act of
protest is illegal
and those people should be arrested. Of
course, because that's and not pardoned.
Are the protest that Wait, wait, stop.
You said not pardoned and not pardoned.
Oh, there you go. Anybody involved in a
violent protest who is doing violence,
that is a crime. Doesn't matter if
they're a citizen, doesn't matter if
they're if they're a a sjourer. I'm I'm
gonna stop using the term illegal,
right? Illegal alien because the Bible
doesn't recognize any such thing. Right?
So, what I'm saying is regardless of who
or what it is, if there is violence,
that should be punished by the law.
Period.
Go ahead. Right. And I really almost
forgot what I was I think I forgot what
I was gonna say cuz cuz I cut you off a
whole bunch of times. Um, can we get all
the clip? Can we get all the clips of
him interrupting me?
Because people love to say I interrupt
him, but he does it too. But go ahead.
But I don't care. You Yeah. You were
asking me what I'm going to speak about.
So Oh, yeah. That was it. Yeah. So my
sermon today is on the king of the north
and the king of the south, but it will
it is going to be something that you
um
have may have never heard before and
some connections with which are
absolutely profound and it's going to be
a sort of a followup on our last two
messages.
So the Holy Spirit is just building.
Please make sure make sure you share
this link because I'm coming I'm coming
at the idea of the king of the south and
the king of the north from a totally
different perspective maybe than
anything you have ever ever ever heard
and it will challenge you. So yeah, so
don't go anywhere. You want to stay
tuned as they say. Well, we do want to
end uh or close this part of our service
with prayer, but please don't go away
because we're coming right back with our
divine worship service and we want you
to be there. Remember, share uh this
link on your social media and like and
invite your friends and family to
church. All right, let's pray. Heavenly
Father, thank you Lord for this uh study
this this morning today. Lord, I pray
Lord that we will as Christians we will
we will stop and think carefully Lord
about um about positions that we hold,
positions that we take for granted that
we would search everything according to
the Bible and to see whether you approve
or not, Lord. So please Lord, help us to
be people of the book in everything that
we say and do. And we thank you Lord. Be
with us in our upcoming service. Uh be
with me as I deliver this message called
Evangelism, the King of the North and
the King of the South. Lord, and uh may
this message have an impact upon us like
like um like very few things have. Lord,
may it open our eyes and our hearts to
something that is crucial that we must
understand. And we thank you, Lord, for
hearing and answering because we ask it
in Jesus name. Amen. Amen. Amen.
[Music]
1 1600 miles away from the nearest
continent, there's a lazy, laid-back
land where the days are long and time
slows down. Just like a tired sea turtle
resting on a white sandy beach. A place
where the minutes feel like hours and
the hours can feel like days. a relaxing
rest where you can pause from the hustle
and bustle of life and just be in the
moment. The locals call it Fiji time. It
simply means that nothing happens in a
hurry and that whatever is supposed to
happen will eventually happen. So relax
and enjoy the wait. But it's more than
just the way the locals view time. It's
the way they view life.
[Music]
To be honest, even though I grew up on
an island, many times I find it
difficult to slow down. There's just so
much to do and so little time in which
to do it. And I know that many task
oriented people like me can relate. But
once you've experienced Fiji or island
time for yourself, you begin to realize
that you've been missing out on
something so essential in life. Because
the reality is that the quality of your
life increases in proportion to your
quality of rest.
Fight back.
[Music]
We could stop the fighting. Today we
live in a world full of appointments,
schedules, deadlines, and cut off dates.
Life is crowded with so much activity,
assignments, and engagements. There are
so many things fighting for our
attention and pulling us in so many
different directions. We live in a task
oriented world that seems to be more
concerned with production rather than
people. And in this fast-paced society
filled with sound bites and flashing
lights, sometimes we find it hard to
even breathe.
It's so easy to get caught up in trying
to make a living that we never really
live. Many people come to the end of
their lives filled with regret,
realizing that their years have been
consumed with things that don't really
matter. There are few things worse than
coming to the end of your days wishing
you had more time to live in the moment.
But here's the good news. In this world
that is constantly on the grind, God is
offering to us Fiji time. Time to trade
in the mess of our stress for the best
of God's rest. Time to decompress from
the pressures of life. Time to enjoy
this precious gift of God called the
present. To be in the here and in the
now, to live in the moment. And while it
is true that in the light of the last
days, we are to live with a sense of
urgency. It is also true that God is
calling us to be still and to know that
he is God. much closer,
closer than it seems. You see, we are
called human beings, not human doings.
And most people get so caught up in
constantly doing that if they forget to
simply be. Friends, if the enemy cannot
make you bad, he will make you busy. He
will crowd your life with so much
clutter that you will have no time to
spend with the one who inhabits
eternity. And without him, life is a
neverending pursuit of happiness that
will eventually lead to devastation,
disappointment, and death.
[Music]
And so, are you sick and tired of being
sick and tired? Are you overwhelmed by
the stresses of life? Do you feel
yourself drowning in a sea of activity,
burdened in a beehive of busyiness,
wrapped up in a web of weariness? Well,
if so, the God of rest says to you
today, "Come unto me, all ye that are
weary and heavy laden, and I will give
you rest. Take my yoke upon you, learn
from me, for I'm meek and lowly in
heart, and you shall find rest unto your
souls. For my yoke is easy and my burden
is light. For in returning and in rest,
you shall be saved. In quietness and
confidence, you shall find your
strength. And as we come to lay down our
burdens at the feet of Jesus and learn
to live more of our lives on Fiji time,
the God of peace shall give us rest for
the rest of our journey. Rest not only
for time, but for all eternity.
[Music]
No more senseless dying. Jesus came to
make us one. To show all others of his
love we need.
We could stop the fighting.
[Music]
No more senseless dying. Jesus came to
make us one to show all others of his
love. We need
[Music]
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Hey, Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
welcome. Welcome back, Living Mana
Church family. So happy that you decided
to continue to worship with us today.
Please put in the chat where you are
viewing from. I know our numbers have
doubled since we started the program.
And so if you have not yet put in the
chat where you're viewing from, please
do that at this time. So we can say a
very special welcome to you. Again, we
are just so very happy uh that you have
decided to come here to Living Mana
online church and worship with our
church family. We are thrilled and
excited to have each and every one of
you. Also, I know that this is Father's
Day weekend. So, want to say happy
Father's Day to all of the fathers out
there. I had an amazing father. I had an
amazing grandfather. and I married an
amazing man who is an amazing father.
So, I want to say happy father's day to
my husband, Pastor Ivor Meyers. He is a
great father uh to our four children and
an amazing grandfather to our
grandchildren and I am so thankful uh to
have him as a husband and as a father to
our children. So, happy Father's Day to
him and to all of you. Okay, we have Tim
from Jacksonville, Florida. Welcome,
Takara. Welcome from Indianapolis. Of
course, you were just on with us. Uh
Jane, um from Mount Ary, Maryland.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. All
right. So, there's more. We have um
Well, Paul, I don't know if you're I
think you're from Maryland, too. You're
saying it's a great Okay. From the great
state of Maryland. Paul, welcome. Happy
Sabbath to you. Uh, Sister Joanne
Stevens, um, from Trinidad and Tobago.
Always good to see you. Uh, Sister
Joanne, welcome.
All right. Good to see everybody here.
Ah, and we have a one in the chat and
the handle says, "Hello, love." So, to
hello, love. Welcome to Living Manage
Church. Uh, this is a completely 100%
online church. We are not just here on
Saturday. the Sabbath, but we are here
all throughout the week with
programming. So, in just a few moments,
I'm going to show you how you can sign
up to get alerts about our different
programming when we're going live. But
just to let you know, we have mental
health Mondays on Monday. We have True
Health Tuesdays. On Tuesdays, we have
prayer. We have prayer all the time, but
we have prayer programming on
Wednesdays. We have two programs, the
power line and power Wednesday. And then
we have a program for the young adults
on Thursday with our young adult, Pastor
Loami Richardson. So, we have lots of
programming going on here. So, you're
going to want to know about all of them.
And again, just in a moment, I'll share
with you on how you can uh sign up to
get alerts and to find out more
information about them as well. So, want
to welcome Brian Thompson from Trinidad.
Good to see you here. Happy Sabbath to
you. and to everyone else who has just
joined joined us for the first time
today. We are so happy that you are
here. So now I want to uh just show you
how you can stay connected to the living
mana church um so that you can be again
reminded when we're going live and when
what programs uh we have going on and
you can do that by signing up to get
connected with Living Mana Church if you
are here in America. That's the way that
that happens. So you all you do is you
can text LMOC to that 8552074107
number and then it would it will
automatically sign you up to get text
alerts so you can know what's going on
with Living Matter Church and what's
happening. But again, that only works
here in the United States. And as I was
reading the list and welcoming
everybody, you could see we have people
from all around the world. And so, um,
you're going to want to sign up for
Mighty Networks, not just to get these
alerts, but on Mighty Networks is where
our community, how we form community
here at Living Manage Church. So, there
you'll be able to learn about all the
different small groups. Uh, you'll get
to message the leaders, meet members,
meet viewing audience. Uh, they're there
on Mighty Network and you also get
alerts and information through Mighty
Network as well. So all of our intern
everybody will get it but that
especially works for our international
viewership and members. So please sign
up for mighty networks. It's right there
in the chat. Um this that's our virtual
church home. So if again if you're
wanting to stay connected to living mana
church that is how you do that. Also
want to let everyone know that we do
have programming for kids and it's
called LOC kids. We have a great team
that leads out in LMOC kids and they
start at 11:30 central time on Sabbath
morning and they go for about an hour
and a half. If you want to sign your
kids up for LMC kids, you can text kids
to that 855 number or you can also email
the leadership team there at lmocid
living manana.urch. And the kids program
is wonderful. They are having fun. they
are learning the deep things in the
Bible and having fun uh while doing so.
So, if you would like to get your kids
involved, they even do uh photo theology
on the level for kids. Um and so they're
learning even those things and doing an
amazing job with that. So, if you want
your kids involved in LOC kids, again,
you're going to want to um text kids to
that 855 number or you can send an email
to the email that's on the screen.
If you would like to become a member of
Living Matter Church. Um there's three
ways that you can do that. you if you
are um already a member of the 7th Day
Adventist Church, but your membership is
at another church and you'd like to
transfer your membership, you can just
send an email to patrice at livinga.live
live and that will get the ball rolling
for you to be able to transfer your
membership or or if you are a Christian
have already been baptized but you would
like to become a 7-day advent 7day
Adventist and a member you can join the
church by profession of faith because
you because that way if you feel like
you don't need to be rebaptized then you
can join by profession of faith and you
can use that same email to do that and
then if you would like to be baptized um
into the 7th Day Adventist Church, you
can do that also. And that same email,
patrice living.live, is the email to use
to be able to do that. And Pastor Myers
will baptize you. So that's very
exciting as well. So that's the email to
be able to become a member for all the
um the the three different uh ways to
become a member. If you are wanting to
have an office meeting with Pastor
Meyers, you use that same email. Patrice
at living.live and she will help you
schedule an appointment with Pastor
Meyers.
We are asking that if you are watching
on power of the lamb YouTube channel
that you would please go to my living
mana YouTube channel and click subscribe
and like. We are trying to grow our
presence the living mana um presence on
um YouTube. And so if you would go again
and press like and subscribe that would
be greatly appreciated.
If you have prayer requests um our
prayer team is very active and so these
are the ways that you can uh let our
prayer give your prayer request to our
prayer team. You can email pray living
manana.urch. If you will join, if you've
joined Mighty Networks, you can put your
prayer request on the prayer wall or you
can text pray for to that 855 number and
our prayer team will pray for your
request until your prayer request is
answered, however God is answering uh
that request. And then we would love to
hear the testimony of how God answered
your prayer and you can send it into
that same email prayer. church and then
Sister Amra can read your testimony of
answered prayer on Sabbath morning
during the I say Sabbath morning like
we're just at a local church. So on
Sabbath, whatever time zone that is for
you. Um and she'll be able to read that
testimony of what God has done for you.
I just want to make another announcement
about the convocation that we were
planning in October. Um that specific
convocation has been cancelled but we
are uh working and beginning to plan
something else. It is still something
that we are going to be able to gather
and fellowship but we will also be doing
service together in uh the city and area
that we go to. So you're not so please
stay tuned for more information about
the event that is going to be put
together. Um so that you can we'd love
to see you so you can be there.
Also you guys saw at Sabbath school we
had we we had two guest the leaders of
Hangouts and Hangouts is a new ministry
that Living Mana Church is starting and
it's just so that you can have more
fellowship together. And if you saw uh
the programming uh this morning um or
this after today our first program it's
morning afternoon it's all it might be
the night time in some areas but during
our first program we had uh Nicole and
Takara on and they were sharing about
the what Hangouts is going to be like
and it's just to worship have fun to get
to know each other be better and it's
just like what it says to hang out and
do Christian fellowship uh in a small
group space. So you don't there's you
don't have to bring anything just
yourself. Um and just it's going to be
great. So um the first information
setting I'm sorry session about hangouts
is Sunday, June 29th uh at 700 p.m.
Central time. And so if you're wanting
to be a a Hangouts host or leader, um
definitely want you to come to that. So
you can scan the QR code there and uh
you can also email at hangoutsman.urch
if you are interested wanting to help
out and to be involved. We would love to
have you be involved with hangouts
because it's a great new ministry. Also
wanted to remind you guys of the uh
prayer online the power line. It has
been amazing. Um that's on YouTube every
um every week at 6:30 p.m. Central. And
again, this is where you can tune in and
they the prayer team, the prayer leaders
are praying for you in real time. So,
you put in your request and they're
going to pray and you can invite your
friends and family and co-workers,
whoever to come and tune in and say,
"Hey, if you're needing special prayer,
this is a a place where they will pray
for you right there on the spot." So, we
definitely want to get the word out
about the power line and would love to
have um you there, your friends, your
family, your co-workers, just spread the
word that this is happening.
Just wanted to remind all of you that
mental health Monday is now taking a
summer break. We had our uh grand finale
program la this past Monday. But do not
fear, we will uh be sharing some of the
past programs um that we have done
because we've been here for three years
now. But the past some of the past
programs, some of the best of the past
programs, I think all the programs are
good, but the best ones we are going to
be reairing them throughout the summer.
So you guys can still because many of
you may not have seen them live or maybe
have never gone back to see them and
there's some really good mental health
information and programs that Dr. White
and myself have done. So we are taking
uh a break from the lives but there will
still be programming going uh for mental
health mon Monday. Now true health
Tuesday is not taking a break and there
was just an amazing program that Dr.
Maria Jose Humel did and that's on the
poison of sugar. My family calls me the
sugar police. So I love that program. Um
so please if you didn't see it, please
go back because it's so important to
know about what sugar is doing uh to
your body. And so uh yeah, and that's
for True Health uh Tuesday. And they're
again they're not taking a break and
they uh will be here. they will be here.
Not she does it every other week. So she
she will uh Dr. Hume will be here um in
two weeks because she just did it this
week. So you're not going to want to
miss that.
Also, this is a reminder that afterlow
and that's the date it moved, but it has
moved. So our afterlow is no longer on
Alter Live, but is on Mighty Networks.
That's why you need to download Mighty
Networks, guys. Because if you want to
be a part of the afterglow and you want
to just fellowship with LMOC members and
viewing audience after the sermon, then
you're not you're going to have to
download Mighty Networks. And what's so
great about the afterglow is it is the
church uh membership and family and the
viewing audience coming together just to
discuss uh their thoughts and and what
they got from Sabbath school, what they
got from the sermon. And it's just a
great time to fellowship. A lot of times
there's there's prayers, there's
singing, there's uh just testimonies.
It's a great time to fellowship. So,
right after the sermon is over, you can
go to the afterglow on mighty networks.
Also, just want to remind you guys about
living mana global. And living mana
global is where we go into all the world
and the languages of the world. And we
are just so happy that we have uh the
technology to be able to do that. And I
just want to show you once again what
that looks like. So please take a
listen.
for
We again we're so thankful for LMLC
global because that helps us to go into
all the world speaking the languages of
the world and right now we we are in
seven languages. We want to grow that.
Um so continue to think of Eloc Global
when you are um thinking about your
giving to Living Manage Church because
it helps us to be able to uh bring more
languages on board. So we are just again
so very thankful that we can do that.
And if please go check out LMLC Global
and see if the the seven if one of the
seven languages or more than one um is
um in a language that you can share with
someone that you know and it might be
helpful to be able to hear Pastor
Meyer's sermons in their native uh
language, then please share share it
with them. um and share on your social
media if you are connected to a
community that speaks that language. So
we are just again so thankful to be able
to have that technology to be able to do
that. And if you would like to continue
or to start giving to Living Matter
Church, just want to let you know how
you can do that. Um you can do this
online by going to adventistgiving.org.
That's adventgiving.org or and you click
in the right hand corner and a virtual
tithe envelope will come drop down and
you will be able to give your tithe
which goes to the Northeastern
Conference because this is our church
living church is a member of the North
Eastern Conference and and that um when
you give your tithe that helps to
support the conference and the worldwide
7th Day Adventist Church. when you give
to our local church budget, it helps to
um support Living Mana Church and the
different all the many different things
that we do. Um and then there's even a
section for the benevolence fund which
you can um give there that helps us to
support uh people when they are um
asking for assistance um for for various
things when they are in need. Um and
there are so many other areas that you
can give to. If you're not wanting to
give online, you can simply send a check
in to Living Mana Church. And there's
the address there on your screen. We
just ask that you please put a little
note to let us know uh where you would
like uh your funds to go. How much is
for tithe, how much is for offering,
benevolence fund or other areas that
Living Mana Church supports. So that's
how you can continue to give or start
giving to support Living Mana Church.
And again, we're so thankful to all of
you that give and support uh Living
Manage Church, not just through your
financial gifts, but also through your
prayers, through showing up each week uh
by putting it on your social media, by
talking about Living Manage Church with
friends and family. It is because of you
that helps this church to continue uh to
go and we are just thankful for God for
giving us uh this mission to to start
this church. said it was really it was
it was as we started by faith because
this had never been done before and God
has grown it into what it is now. But he
is continuing to grow this church and uh
just giving us wisdom on how to on what
steps we need to take next. And so we
just um continue to ask that you pray
for Living Mana Church and our and the
leadership that we will make the right
decisions that God wants us to make. So
again, we are just so thankful for for
you and for your presence and for your
giving. And we're thankful to God. And
so I just want to say give a prayer of
thanksgiving to him, thanking him for
all his many blessings. So please bow
your heads with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, just want to
thank you uh for all that you do for
Living Mana Church. Just want to thank
you for all the volunteers, Lord. All
everyone who supports this church and
and makes it work. Lord, it's not one
person. It is everyone. This is all
hands on deck. And we've been so blessed
by so many to make this church work. And
we're just so thankful uh from the
bottom of our hearts. And most
important, we're so thankful to you,
God, for just bringing this all
together. Lord, I know many are here in
church, but they have had a hard week.
Some have had a hard week. They have had
financial struggles. Uh some have had
marital struggles, parenting struggles,
health struggles, Lord. There's so many
things that we go through on this earth,
Lord. And we know that even when it
doesn't look okay, that you, like my
shirt says, you have a plan. And so, we
just have to trust you and you give us
that peace. And so Lord, I pray for all
the marriages, all everyone who's going
through health issues, um the parents
who are trying to parent their children,
Lord, for um financial issues that
people are having. Lord, I pray for all
of that. And I ask that you will um just
answer their prayers and bless them in
the areas that they are needing to be
blessed. Lord, I pray for Pastor Meyers
and I just ask that he will be filled
with the Holy Spirit and whatever the
message that you have given him today
will be a blessing to all of us. We ask
all these things in Jesus' name. Amen.
[Music]
A father, it's more than a title. It's a
calling. A high and holy assignment, a
gift from God. A father is a protector,
a provider, a quiet strength when storms
roll in. He leads not just with words,
but by example, a living lesson of
patience, integrity, and grace.
He teaches and he listens. He learns
alongside us. He doesn't just show up,
he stands firm. In a world full of
noise, he's the steady voice of truth.
In a world that runs, he walks beside
us. A father is a hero in the eyes of
his children and a gift in the eyes of
God. Fatherhood is a precious
opportunity and a divine responsibility.
Thank you, dads, for embracing your
calling, for being the hands and heart
of the father above. We honor you today.
Happy Father's Day.
[Music]
I've heard a thousand stories of what
they think you're like, but I've heard
the tender whisper of love
and the dead of night Can't you tell me
that you're pleased and that I'm
never alone.
You're a good good father. It's who you
are.
It's who you are.
It's who you are. And I'm loved by you.
It's who I am.
I seen
many searching for answers
far and wide. But I know we're all
searching for answers.
Only you proide. Yes. to know just what
we need before we we say your word.
You're a good good father. It's who you
are.
It's who you are.
It's who you are. And I'm loved by you.
It's who I am.
You are perfect in all your ways.
You are perfect in all your ways
to us.
Love so
uneniable.
I I can hardly speak.
Peace so
unexplainable.
I I can hardly think as you call me.
Deeper still as you call me.
Deeper still into love.
Love.
You're a good good father. It's who you
are.
It's who you are.
It's who you are. And I'm loved by you.
It's who I am.
You are perfect in all your ways.
to us.
Sing that again. You are perfect in all
of your ways. Yes, you are perfect in
all of your ways. Jesus, you are perfect
in all of your ways to us.
Here
at Living Mana, we bear each other's
burdens. When you need support or
prayer, when you're feeling discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that that we may obtain mercy and
find grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Amen. Amen. Let's try again. Take two.
Greetings, saints of the most high.
Isn't it wonderful that we serve a God
of second chances? I mean, right. We
serve the God of And it's another thing.
It's great that it's Sabbath all day.
Okay. So, happy Sabbath, saints of the
most high God. Welcome to another
edition of Living Manners Prayer and
Praise Time. I am here with my lovely
bride Amra as always. And I'm going to
tell you what, it doesn't matter what
happens. Our God is still on the throne.
All right? And uh we're ready to give
him praise. Amen. And so, you know what?
We I love y'all. I saw you guys. You
said, you know, let's pray. I saw the
warriors, living man of warriors in the
chat, members in the chat. Let's pray.
That's right. Look, I thank God that I'm
just that's just it now. You know, I'm
not expecting anything to just go
smoothly
ever. He's a God of doovers. The Bible
says through much tribulation shall we
enter into the kingdom, right? So
believe that. That's just how it is,
right? And we are we are spiritual
stormtroopers, beloved. We're either in
the middle of a storm or we coming out
of one storm heading into another.
That's just our existence. So, praise
God for being so wonderful, being so
faithful, and for helping us to get it
together. I have no idea what that was
about. I honestly don't. Everything
Everything was connected. Everything's
hooked up. But we're learning. Amen.
Together. Together. So, look, when we
heard that worship song, Good Father, it
reminded me of made me think about
something. Can we get together, saints
of the most high God, and if you will,
just put it in the chat. Happy Father's
Day, Lord. To him, the greatest father
of all. God, we give you praise today.
Happy Father's Day to you. The most
incredible Father there ever was and
ever will be. Wonderful Lord. Wonderful
God. You know, um it's because of our
good good father in heaven that I was
able to stand by my father uh uh at his
on his deathbed. Amar was there with me.
Saw my father take his last breath. And
you know, my father was never there for
me. He was very abusive and uh a lot of
pain, a lot of hurt. But it was because
of the love of our father that I was
able to look at him and tell him that I
loved him in his last breaths. I
remember when we disconnected the life
support and my father heard my voice for
the first time in a long time and all of
his vitals went up. We were watching
that. We were like, "Oh Lord, what's
going on?" But it was the love of God.
Tear came down. Remember that? Yeah, I
remember that. And so all of you who um
today are wishing happy father's day,
look, remember we serve the greatest
father of all and he is he's a wonderful
miracle working, life-changing father.
See you all there in the chat and all
you earthly fathers. Happy Father's Day
to you. Happy Father's Day, pastor.
Definitely amazing father and spiritual
father. Thank you so much, brother. Uh
truly do love you. And uh um uh he
sometimes reminds me that he tells me I
remind him of his big brother. But uh
man, you a spiritual father and God has
made you that. And I and I honor and
respect you in that regard. And all the
other fathers of living mana love y'all
too. Thank you so much. Uh first timers
Terry Parker has her nephew Tommy here.
Tommy, welcome brother. Hope you're
still watching. Thank you for joining us
for the huddle. We loved you this
morning. Hello love. Good to see you
here with us. Uh, we are honored by your
presence. And T, T, it's your first
time. I remember you here from the deep
south. I'm from the south, too. I've
lost my accent. I thought folk were
laughing at me when I first came out
here. I said, "Look, I got to I got to
You can turn it on though. Yeah, when
necessary." Okay. So, but uh thank the
Lord for y'all first timers joining us.
We love y'all. And uh thank thank God
for y'all being here with us. I also
want to uh really give uh h a praise to
God for this hangout ministry that we
saw Sister Takara and Nicole and we're
praying for y'all. We'll continue to
pray for y'all. That is breach mending
ministry because as you remember from
Nehemiah Nehemiah chapter 4 verse 19,
everybody needs to go look that up. When
Nehemiah told him that the work is great
and we're separated one from another on
the wall. There are many of us laboring
in the Lord's vineyard and we're on the
wall, but yet there are breaches amongst
us that need to be repaired. We need to
be mending these breaches. And I don't
want to get into that too deeply right
now, but thank God for a ministry like
that. And what we're seeing happening in
our special ops teams, if you haven't
been a part of a special ops team, and I
know many of you watching probably
haven't had an opportunity to, let me
tell you, there is a chemistry and there
is a bond and amazing family connection
on these ops team. We have the vision
and pastor certainly has the vision that
we want to get every member in living
mana
in at least three to four member team
praying for one another and and just you
know laboring together and loving on
each other and bonding till we have this
whole church community bonded together
and you know not just saying you know we
have the same doctrines we go to the
same church and stuff but to really get
to know one another and really love one
another and really to share in one
another's burdens. That's our vision for
this ministry. Form true friendships and
relationships. We are going to be
spending eternity together. So that's
right. Let's get to know each other
here. Right. That's right. And I'm a
social butterfly. I love that people. So
I am so looking forward to this. You
know ministry. Amber's one of these
people that she's never met somebody
that's not a friend. I'm just like, is
everybody a friend? He teases me all the
time. Look, strangers are just friends I
haven't met yet. How's that?
That's interesting. I like that
question.
Praise God. And I want to say, brother
Tennessee, you know, you said that this
ministry is a blessing to to us. But
listen, brother. Never doubt it for one
minute. You are a blessing, my brother.
God bless you. Stand strong in the
faith. continue to continue to minister
and encourage and to put those uh
thought-provoking challenging questions
in the chat. We love that. Love that my
man. I wanted to say thank you to pastor
and sister Atante for, you know, being
loving and sensitive and courageous
enough to address those topics like we
did today on immigration. And I I man
beautifully handled. pastor is such a
progressive thinker and uh I learned so
much and I'm so inspired by the approach
they take to things and uh biblical
approach and that's we want to learn to
think biblically and I love the way
pastor had us thinking through the
biblical process to come to the
conclusions that we need to come to that
we can live with you know and that we
can hang on to and then helps us to
understand everything that's going on in
the world in the biblical perspective it
makes sense and when it doesn't make
sense to us there's a whole lot of
anxiety And so for those of you who may
be experiencing anxiety because you may
be directly affected by these
immigration issues or you may know
someone that is, we know people who are
and um we want to let you know that we
are aware. We love you. We're praying
for you and those of you who are
affected by all this other noise going
on. There's a lot going on in the world
right now. But I tell you, when we learn
to think through it biblically and put
it in the biblical perspective, there is
a peace. Jesus says, "My peace I live
with you, not the peace that the world
gives you. The peace I give you, the
world cannot take that peace away. It is
a supernatural peace beyond
understanding when we put our faith in
the word of the living God, in God
himself. And so, we want to encourage
you today. Uh, stand strong. We we're
praying for you that God will lead you
into a deeper understanding of his word.
So, you'll have that peace. You can have
that peace no matter what's going on.
And so, just want to say this. I know
I'm talking a little bit more than I
wanted to. Hey Christy in South
Carolina, I wanted to shout you out, my
sister. love you back there at home. Uh,
keep hanging strong and keep praying.
But I did want to say this, saints. No
matter what's going on, even no matter
how much noise there is in the world,
we're still called to give the good news
of the gospel. Amen. We're still called
to share the good news. We're still
called to be salt. We're still called to
be light. And that is why it's so
important that when Pastor Natante and
all of us start talking about really
getting a hold of God like for real for
real get a hold of him, then we can
still and that's the only way to do what
we've been called to do with all of the
stuff that's going on. We believe that
the enemy wants us telling his news
stories rather than telling the good
news story. And so, uh, get a hold of
the supernatural power of God and let's
continue to declare he's on the throne
no matter what's going on. Can we say
amen?
Hallelujah. Well, that's the tagline for
the power line. That's right. If y'all
haven't been to the power line yet on
Wednesdays, please join us. Please join
us for the power line. And by the way,
the power line is not just what you get
on and have prayer requests going back
and forth. It's an evangelistic outreach
tool that all of the church can get
involved with. He says, "Well, how?" Get
that link and share that link with
somebody you know or maybe somebody you
don't know. might be somebody in your
local supermarket or at your hospital,
at your convolescent home. Maybe
somebody just out there that you run
into in in your community. Uh share the
link and say, "Hey, what can I pray for
you?" We found that during co I don't
want to go too far here, but we found
that during co the concept of digital
evangelism really took off just by
simply saying through prayer evangelism,
hey, can I pray for you? Yeah. And when
through prayer, we build meaningful
relationships. Once we build those
meaningful relationships, you can invite
people in and say, "Hey, come see what
we're about. Come see who we are. Come
see what we're building. Join us for
church. You know, join us on Monday.
Join us on Tuesday. Join us on
Wednesday. Join us on any day of the
week. We have something going on.
Friday, Revelation, Bible study, just on
and on and on and on. So, we can keep
going, but uh God, we we we just want to
say we love y'all. We thank God for you.
Again, it is an honor and a privilege.
family, let's stick together and let's
get this work done in Jesus name. Amen.
All right, praise report time. Praise
report time. Now, before I share the
praise reports, which we have quite a
few today, praise God. Just a reminder,
if you have a prayer request or a praise
report or you would like to join the
prayer team or a special ops prayer team
under the prayer team umbrella, please
send an email to pray
livingmana.urch.
If you would like to request a special
ops prayer team for yourself or a loved
one, please send an email to spec ops.
That's s pops
livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry on mighty networks, please send
an email to women at livingmana.urch.
And finally, if you would like to join
the men's ministry, please send an email
to sevenloaves. That's s ven l o a
velmana.urch.
Amen. All right, praise report number
one coming from Shaunene Wright.
22year-old Casey, my son Joseph and
daughter-in-law Tiffany's friend whom we
were praying for after his motorcycle
accident, is recovering better than
expected. Praise God. He is able to walk
now and there is no severe brain damage.
Joseph said, "Thank you from all the
families involved. Loc prayer warriors,
prayers are appreciated. Praise God.
Amen. From Olivia, blessings to you all.
VBS is doing well. Some hiccups, but God
came through with us. Praise God for the
commitment from the parents and
children, the leaders and volunteers.
Truly, he is a God of miracles. Overall,
the children are learning that God is
real and can be trusted. Thank you for
your prayers and please continue to keep
us in your prayers.
from Pauline Goodine.
Thank you family for all your prayers.
The court dismissed my case. Praise the
Lord. I do have the option to counter
sue. Please pray with me for the Lord to
guide me on what he will have me to do.
Amen. Thanks family. And then um she
submitted another this was the original
prayer. Please pray for Mr. Ellis. He is
asking for prayer for the mass on his
bladder that uh that it will not be
cancerous. He is also struggling to
forgive himself for what he has done to
his wife. In the praise report, the mass
is not cancerous. Praise
Amen. from sungazing.
I believe a couple of these are actually
praise reports from the power line last
Wednesday. They are praise report for
God. Uh, craving time out so I can
study. Haven't been working much this
last month. He allowed me to spend
Thursday night through Friday with my
family. From Diane Martinez, praise
report. I went to do a stress test on
Tuesday and I want to praise God for
receiving good news. Everything was
good.
from Terry Parker. Original prayer
request was, "Please pray for John
Depazinski
and his wife Michelle. John suffered a
massive stroke Wednesday night and is on
a ventilator. Michelle underwent an
extensive back surgery recently. Pray
for God's will and praise him for the
strong faith they both have. Pray the
Holy Spirit fills them with overflowing
strength, endurance, peace, comfort, and
healing. I thank God for the support
they have from family, friends,
neighbors, and the church in Jesus'
powerful name. Amen. Also asking prayer
for my daughter Serena that she can get
in to see the ENT, that's the ear, nose,
and throat specialist, and get her
hearing aids sent off for repair by June
30th. Complicated issues with insurance
provider. Pray knowing the Holy Spirit
will untangle this mess. Amen. And the
update. Hello. I have praise reports to
share with our family. First, John
passed peacefully Saturday evening.
Michelle is leaning into her faith and
we are all trusting God for his promises
knowing John entered God's rest and we
will see him soon and very soon. Serena
has an appointment this week to get her
hearing aid repaired. Amen and amen. God
is so good to give wonderful prayer
warriors and to answer us so quickly.
Have a beautiful week with many God
sightings from Charlotte Stanforth.
Praise report. My broken bones are
healing and the doctors say surgeries
are not necessary. Hallelujah. Praise
the Lord. Amen. Amen. And finally, from
Renee Hallebertton,
my daughter Madison is home from the
hospital after spending a month and a
week there. That's a long time to be in
the hospital. Please continue to keep us
in prayer because she is still healing
and the work is not done. Amen. You know
what? I remember I remember a lot of
these um I remember a lot of these these
prayer requests. These praise reports
were prayer requests and I remember them
from um the power line and some from
here. And so we want to thank y'all. You
know, uh, I see something in the chat
and the Lord just keep bringing it to my
eye and that's you, Sister Ramona.
You know,
Ramona, you're such a a a steadfast and
a consistent witness and encouragement.
I want to I just really want to from my
heart today say really thank you, Sister
Ramona. You know, uh, sometimes you'll
see someone in the church that the Lord
has placed and, you know, unassuming,
not really loud, don't hear a lot from,
but, you see them consistently, always
being an encouragement and a witness,
and I want to thank you for that, Sister
Ramona. You are a blessing. We see you
this morning. I wanted to send that
shout out from my heart to you. I just
also want to thank everyone who is
submitting their praise reports. I think
it's so encouraging and such a blessing
to hear how God is answering. I mean, he
answers in his in his timing. Sometimes
it's not always what we think it's going
to look like, but um it's just such a
huge encouragement and hope in our own
struggles when we see how the Lord is
working through other people's lives.
So, please keep submitting them, keep
bringing in those praise reports, and we
love sharing them with you. Amen. So,
don't lose hope. I mean, when he takes
you into a storm and brings you out on
the other side, I mean, you're looking
at Psalm 107:es 21-31. That's the
beginning of a storm that God himself
commanded the stormy winds and wave to
come up. And then when they were at
their wits end and called out to him, he
commanded the storm to be a calm. God is
provoking a response out of us and using
us to be a witness to others and a
testimony to others. So, thank you so
much again, Sister Ramona. I see you in
there just encouraging everybody else,
but uh certainly an encouragement to me.
So, be encouraging. Bless my sister.
Also want to remember Sister Gigi is
literally working under fire. Um and we
want to keep her as a church, as a body.
This is our little sister, you know, and
uh we love her. She's uh our Swiss Army
knife doing a little bit of everything
here at Living Mana and uh right now
working. She's working today, you know,
uh in the in the Lord's vineyard. But
let's let's let's together pray for her
that God will keep her and protect her.
And we know he will. He will do that. Uh
she she's right now in Minnesota doing
her internship there. But uh uh we want
to we want to seriously every day do
keep her surrounded with prayer and the
love of God uh because she is an
absolute blessing to her to all of us.
So um but when we're getting ready to go
into prayer right now and um and we're
going to bring up one of our special
prayer warriors who we love is always I
mean just as busy as she can be, always
working, always serving. And so as she
gets ready to come, I just want to say
only truth. I see that powerful
testimony you put there in the chat
said, "The Lord is in total control. He
knows the the the temporal trials we are
going through on this planet." 2
Corinthians 4:17. Amen. Our light
affliction which is but for a moment.
The Bible says it workketh the far more
exceeding and eternal weight of glory
while we look not at the things which
are seen but at the things which are not
seen. Thank you for sharing that word.
That's a powerful word right there.
Encourage everybody. Go read 2
Corinthians chapter 4. It's beautiful,
beautiful revelation. And so we want to
bring up right now our beloved uh
warette, sister Annette Rivas, and she's
going to lead
and let him use you, sis. Hi, Annette.
Hello. Hello, everyone. Blessings,
living mana. Such a pleasure to be here.
Blessing to have you, sister.
Amen. Amen. So, um, with that being
said, I just want to continue to
encourage everyone to continue to put
your prayer requests in the chat. Um, I
did, uh, grab as many as I could up
until just a few minutes ago. Um, and
just rest assure if you don't hear your
prayer requests being prayed over live.
Trust me, we have our um, prayer
warriors praying over them live there in
the chats. And uh we do collect every
single prayer request and we do pray
over them throughout the whole week. Um
so and and and it's beautiful to see
these praise reports because it it just
shows us how beautiful our God is and
how he um listens and answers our
prayers. So it's always a privilege to
to be here and pray alongside you all.
Amen. Amen. Let us pray.
Heavenly Father,
we humbly come to your throne of grace,
Lord,
asking for forgiveness of sin, Lord,
asking that you cover us with the blood
of Jesus and make us worthy to be in
your presence at this very moment, Lord.
Lord, as we intercede on behalf of our
brothers and sisters, Lord, we just
thank you for this privilege that you
give us that we we have we can access
you 24/7, Lord, and we can come to your
throne of grace on behalf of our
brothers and sisters. Lord, at this very
moment, I would like to lift up my dear
sister Ashlin Ashley Owens. Lord, she
put prayers requests in the chat. Um her
first prayer request was praying for
safety for all those at pro that are
protesting today that all will be um
nonviolent and peaceful Lord and uh we
touch and pray in agreement with our
sister in this request Lord. We know
that our uh country right now is um a
bit divided, Lord, and um so many people
are trying to um just voice their
concerns um during these protests. And
so we just pray, Lord, that you continue
to be with our country and all of these
uh peaceful protesters, Lord, that they
can continue to just express their
concerns and um be heard accordingly,
Lord. and um may you allow that um
negative feelings of of um of anger or
violence to to be put away and put aside
during these these times of peaceful
protest. We're praying, heavenly father,
that you just allow everyone to be able
to just get along and um be able to
share their opinions without having um
having to be attacked, Lord. And so we
just pray, heavenly father, that you
continue to be with with all of the
people that are um doing um
demonstrations this week. Lord, may your
holy spirit just be amongst the crowds,
Lord, and just remain and keep the
peace, Lord, as much as possible. We
also want to continue to pray, Lord. Um
she also requested for prayer for people
and families in Iran and Israel right
now. Many are waking up to horror,
horror and destruction. War is not the
answer. We pray for the peace only the
Lord can give. Lord and and that is
true. Lord, we have a few people asking
for prayer on behalf of Israel and what
is going on in the Middle East. Um Lord,
we pray that you continue to to just
lead out in in um in these areas, Lord.
That you protect the innocent. Um Lord,
we we know that violence is not the
answer. Lord, you called us to love one
another and and um be at peace with one
another, Lord, and and to treat one
another as we would like to be treated.
And so we just ask heavenly father that
you continue to just be amongst um the
leaders of these countries that you can
reveal to them um
the error lord of of taking these types
of tactics Lord and and how it affects
um not only the people in their
countries but it also affects people all
around the world Lord. It it just brings
a lot of confusion and um nervousness
and and chaos, Lord. And we pray that
you just continue to work it out, Lord,
on behalf of of these countries and the
people that are living in these
countries, Lord. Keep them safe. Uh send
your angels to a camp around your
people, Lord, and and help them, Lord.
Give them a way out, Lord. We continue
to also pray for our sister Ashley's
other prayer requests that she did not
put in the prayer chat, Lord, but that
we have been praying over. So we
continue to lift up her health, her
family, her children, Lord, her
finances. Continue continuing to ask,
Lord, that you cover her, Lord, and her
whole family. You know the end from the
beginning, Lord. And so we just lift up
our dear sister Ashley and her family to
your throne. Asking, Lord, that you
continue to work work it all out for
their good, Lord. Um continuing to also
pray, Lord, for Renee, Lord. She um Oh,
it was her praise report, Lord. We uh
sister Amra just um mentioned her praise
report, Lord. And so we thank you, Lord,
that you have been coming through for
our dear sister Rene's daughter and we
continue to pray, Lord, that you
continue to allow her health to um get
better and um that you lead um the
family to the remedies and the doctors,
Lord, that they are needing to to speak
with to continue in this health journey
that you have them in, Lord. But at
least they see, Lord, your hand at work.
They see that you are ordering their
steps and that you are allowing
everything to fall into place on behalf
of their daughter and her health. And so
we praise you and thank you for that.
Lord, we continue to pray for um um
sister Gigi. Lord, she put a prayer
request for our dear sister Jennifer
Booth for her health, specifically her
blood sugar levels. Lord, we praise you
and thank you for our dear sister
Jennifer. Lord, a lot of people don't
know, but she works fervently behind the
screens, Lord, here in Living Mana. Our
sister is one of the main ones that
helps that helps out in the lights team.
And um and she she works very hard,
Lord. And we just praise you and thank
you for our sister Jennifer, Lord. Um
you recently came through also for our
dear sister Jennifer's mom, and we
praise you and thank you for that. Um we
continue to put Sister Jennifer's health
in your hands, Lord. Asking that you um
continue to lead and guide her, Lord, to
to the doctors that will help her, Lord,
um in regulating her uh blood sugars and
helping her and and um and each area of
her health, Lord. You know the end from
the beginning. This is just part of it,
Lord. And we just know Lord that you are
a good father and that you are um
working it out also for our sister's
good and you are leading and guiding her
and bringing healing to her. Lord, thank
you for that. Continue to bless her in
this health journey that you have her
in. Lord, we also continue to pray for
our dear sister Gigi, Lord, and and um
the victims as well of the Minnesota and
the families that are that were victims
in the shooting there, Lord, and the
protesting going on there as well, Lord.
uh the world Lord we are we can see
heavenly father that your second coming
is just so very close. You know you tell
us in your word Lord that as soon as we
see the the the leaves changing color we
know that your second coming is is near
and and we see Lord we can see the
changes. We can feel it Lord our our our
souls tells us that we are needing to be
preparing for that second coming. And so
we just ask heavenly father that you
know um as all of these things that you
have already prophesied that we're to
happen in these last days Lord that you
keep us gired up in you that you
continue to help each and every one of
us uh to be in your will and to do our
part Lord. You have created us for such
a time as this. And so we pray heavenly
father that you continue to use us and
um and help us Lord do your will for
such a time as this. be with all of the
victims, Lord. The the the senators, the
governors, the the people affected,
Lord, with this this um attack there in
Minnesota. You know them. Be with their
families, the people that are grieving
at this time, Lord. Um may you just help
them, Lord. If they don't know you,
Lord, we're pleading the merits of the
blood of Jesus over their lives that you
can remove the veils from their eyes,
the veils that the enemy has placed
there to keep them blinded and doing
things that are against your will. May
you just remove it Lord and may you
allow them to see um the damage that
they are doing Lord and and just be with
this situation altogether heavenly
father our dear sister Sharon Fay shared
a Bible verse Matthew 5:9 that says
blessed are the peacemakers for they
shall be called the children of God and
that's what we're seeking Lord we're
wanting to keep the peace we're wanting
to to um to show your light and your
love to the world Lord so continue to be
with these um with these demonstrations
and all of the people affected. Uh we
continue to pray over Sister um Leela
Peterson. Lord, she asks in her prayer
request, continue to pray for us to be
able to move to Idaho and for the Holy
Spirit to anoint Wes Wes's lips as he
has Bible studies with the coworker over
Daniel and Revelation. Lord, what a
beautiful prayer request, Lord. And
we've been praying for our sister for
quite a bit of time already with this
move, Lord. and we praise you and thank
you, Lord, that you um are keeping it in
her mind and her heart to continue to
pray over the the move to Idaho as human
beings. Lord, it is easy for us to just
make up our mind and make our own
decisions and do things, Lord, without
even consulting you. And our sister and
our brother are requesting, Lord, for
guidance and for for you to open the
doors in order for them to be able to
make this move, Lord, to Idaho. And so
if it's in your will for them to do
that, Lord, we continue to pray, Lord,
that you align everything up on their
behalf so that they are able to make
that move accordingly, Lord. And may it
be in your perfect timing. May you
continue to just give them peace and
knowing that you are aligning everything
up and um and that you will signal them
when it is time for them to do the move,
Lord. and um and if it's even in your
will to for them to move, Lord, may you
just make it as clear as day for them,
Lord, for these decisions in these last
days, Lord. And be with Wes, Lord. It's
an important task that he is taking on
here, speaking to his coworker about
your word and about the things that are
going on in Revelation and in Daniel. So
we continue to ask Lord that you empty
west of self and that you can fill him
with your holy spirit Lord so that
everything that he says and does be
according to your will as he is leading
others to you heavenly father help him
be that light and use him mightily
heavenly father um Lord we continue to
also pray for sister Jodia Mccclure
she's asking for prayer um she believes
um she is um she has blood poisoning
Lord, and uh you know what's going on
with our dear sister Jod. Heavenly
Father, um you know what her body is
reacting to and so we pray heavenly
father that you allow the medical staff
that is attending to her or if she
hasn't gone to the doctor that you may
lead and guide her to um the doctors
that will help her with this situation
that she is going through with her blood
and that that poisoning. Lord, um
sometimes, you know, lead can we can eat
a a a great amount of lead and it it can
actually make us sick, Lord. And so,
whatever it is that is causing her to
feel feel ill, Lord, may you reveal it
to her and may you just put your healing
hand over her body and help her recover
from this from this um illness that she
is going through. Uh Lord, we we want to
also pray for our dear sister Grace and
our dear sister Ruth. They both just put
in the prayer I mean in the chat needed
prayer please. And so Lord, you know
Sister Grace and you know Sister Ruth,
you know the end from the beginning. You
created them for such a time as this
Lord. And so we pray heavenly father
that you be with each individual
situation that they're dealing with.
That you um may you lead and guide them
Lord to what it is that you would have
them do in these situations. May you
bless their finances, their health,
Lord, um their uh spiritual walk with
you. Um and every area, Lord, that
they're lacking. May you just fill it
for them, heavenly father. We just ask,
heavenly father, that you continue to
lead and guide them and their families.
We're pleading the merits of the blood
of Jesus over both of them. And Lord, we
also pray for brother Tennessee. Um he
is asking prayer that the preachers in
our church will not take advantage of
the fears of members in their church to
capitalize for self gain. Um and
heavenly father Lord we we we we know
heavenly father that as humans sometimes
when we put self in in place
we tend to do things that are against
your will. And so that's what we're
praying against for each leader all over
our conferences all over our um not only
locally, Lord, but worldwide. Um Lord,
may you continue to allow each of the
people that have heard your calling and
taken the stand to preach as pastors,
Lord, or as leaders in churches that you
continue to remind them, Lord, that it
is not within themselves to make
decisions, but it's it's through your
Holy Spirit. Um, and so may you just
continue to allow them to put self aside
and humble themselves to allow your Holy
Spirit to be the one uh leading and
guiding out in their churches, Lord, and
in the conferences, Lord. Um, and we
just ask a special prayer, Lord, of
covering over all our pastors, Lord,
because they are they are literally the
ones in in the front lines, Lord. They
get targeted so much and um get
attacked. And so we just pray, heavenly
father, that you continue to just lead
and guide these pastors, that you
continue to remove those, Lord, that
aren't supposed to be leading your
churches. Remove them from those
positions, Lord, so that they don't lead
more people astray, Lord. And um just
protect, heavenly father, those that are
being sincere and faithful to you and
give them that strength and perseverance
that they're needing for such a time as
this, Lord. Um Lord, we we also continue
to pray for um faith. Faith mentions um
pray for peace over Israel and the
entire neighborhood regions, for
protection, for open hearts in the in
this shakening
that many would seek the hope found in
Jesus, Lord. And so we do pray Lord that
even during these times of of of
uncertainty and grief and war Lord um
that more and more people can come to
the realization Lord that living a life
here in this world without you is not
it's not a life worth living Lord you
know this peace that surpasses all
understanding it's the only thing that
can get us through these trials that
we're going through Lord and so that's
our prayer for each individual that is
you know going through these these um
trials in and in and war areas, Lord,
that they may come to know you, Lord, so
that they can live a life knowing that
no matter what happens in their
surroundings, that you have them and
that it it's all temporary. All of the
things that are going through um that
we're going through now are all
temporary and we have something to look
forward to, which is a a a everlasting,
loving, peaceful life alongside you,
Lord. And and so continue to just remind
everyone, Lord, and and help those that
don't know to come into that um
realization of of um of that everlasting
life that you are offering us, Lord. And
may they take full advantage and may
they be able to um allow you, Lord, to
live in their hearts and and show them
that peace that surpasses all
understanding. Continue to just be with
everyone that is in these war areas.
Lord, comfort them, Lord. Shield them
and help them, Lord. A lot of them are
just, you know, they're they have they
they just need you, Lord. They need you
and your peace and and comfort, Lord.
And so, we just pray that you um that
you continue to just be with them, each
each person, Lord, that is going through
these trials. Um Lord, we're praying for
also um Christy.
She says, um, Christy asks for prayer
for the prayer warriors to pray. Please
pray for Selena who lost her husband due
to cancer. Also pray for our families,
friends, churches, country, and leaders.
Pray that the ongoing wars will not
become global, Lord. And so we touch and
pray in agreement with Christie, Lord.
And we're we're lifting up Selena, Lord,
that um just recently widowed, Lord, and
you know the situation there. We have so
many, Lord, that have lost loved ones,
Lord. We have so many single mothers out
there, Lord, that will be celebrating
mother and father's day without their
better half and and the father of their
children alongside them. And so, we just
want to say a special prayer for them,
heavenly father, that your comfort may
um emerge them um during this time of
grief. May you um may you just pour down
love and peace and um understanding over
them Lord and help them Lord during this
time. It is a difficult time heavenly
father. And so we just pray that you
continue to just lead and guide them,
protect them and and comfort them Lord
in these times. be with um um with
Selena as she, you know, is going
through this griefing process um losing
her spouse uh due to cancer and and be
with all of the people that are going
through the same thing as she is.
Heavenly Father, we just pray that that
your Holy Spirit, which is the the
comforter, Lord, to comfort them during
these times. Heavenly Father. Um and
also um as we prayed before, continue to
be with with our churches, our families,
Lord, our loved ones. Um and and
continue to lead in each area. Heavenly
Father, we also want to um lift up
Living Faith. Um this is the last prayer
request I was able to to pick up, Lord.
And living faith is praying is asking
for prayer. Uh prayer for my girlfriend
and I to be baptized and married Lord.
And what a beautiful prayer that is.
What a beautiful request that is that
they are trying to do things according
to your will Lord. And they are
preparing. Um and so Lord we continue to
pray that you be with uh living faith.
You know you know them by name. You know
them by number. You know exactly what
they are needing. And so we just pray,
heavenly father, that you align
everything up, Lord, as they're seeking
to do your will and um you know, taking
the steps to be able to um be married,
Lord, and be one in you. And so we just
pray over them, asking that you evenly
yoke them and that they can be a power
couple for your honor and your glory to
further your kingdom for such a time as
this, Lord. and any prayers, Lord, that
we uh I wasn't able to um find or or
attach to this prayer request that I'm
reading over right now. Lord, I just the
ones that weren't even typed in the
chat. Lord, all of those silent prayer
requests, Lord, we praying that you
continue to work in and through each
individual life, Lord. We're praying
that your will may be done in each
individual life, Lord, because that is
the only way we know that we are um in
your will, Lord, is that if we are
falling um according and doing things
according to your will. And so, Lord,
continue to be with everyone, heavenly
father, and their and their prayer
requests. And we and be with each
individual prayer warrior as well,
heavenly father. continue to keep us
girded up in you and help us do your
will for such a time as this. Praising
you and thanking you, Lord. Also praying
over Pastor Myers and the sermon that he
will be sharing with us today, Lord. May
you anoint your his lips, Lord. And may
you allow your Holy Spirit to be the one
to speak through him, Lord. Prepare the
minds and the hearts of all of us, Lord,
that are um present. allow the seeds
that are planted to fall in good solid
and in good uh fertile soil, Lord, so
that it can produce much fruit for your
honor and glory. We praise you and thank
you once again for the privilege of
prayer and we humbly request all of
these things in the precious name of
your son Jesus Christ. Amen and amen.
Amen. Thank you so much, Sister Renee.
Beautiful. Amen. Amen. Glory to God.
[Music]
You were not hidden.
There's never been a moment you were
forgotten.
You were not hopeless.
Though you have been broken, you're
innocent stolen.
I hear you whisper
underneath
your breath.
I hear your sos,
your sos.
[Music]
I will send out an army to find you in
the middle of the darkest night is true.
I will rescue you.
There is no distance
that cannot be covered over and over.
You're not defenseless.
I'll be your shelter and I'll be your
armor.
I hear you whisper underneath
your breath.
I hear your sos.
Your sos.
Yay.
Oh, and I will send out an army to find
you in the middle of the darkest
tonight. It's true. I will resue you.
Oh, and I will never stop marching to
reach you. In the middle of the hardest
fight, it's true. I will rescue you.
Oh, I hear the whisper
underneath your breath.
I hear you whisper, "You have nothing
left."
Oh, and I will send out an army to find
you in the middle of the darkest
tonight. It's true. I will resue you.
Oh, and I will never stop watching to
reach you in the middle of the hardest
fight. It is true. I will rescue you.
Oh, and I will resue you.
Oh, I will rescue
you.
Oh,
I will rescue you.
According
as it is written. According how?
According as it is written. According as
it is suggested. According as it is
written. Made up. As it is written.
Opinion. As it is written. I warn it. As
it is written. As it is written.
Unforgiven. You give Bible chapter and
verse right now.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat
up
here.
[Music]
You give Bible chapter verse right now.
Amen. Amen. Uh, happy Sabbath Church
family. Um, graphics team. Thank you.
That was powerful. That was powerful.
Um,
I want to just again
uh welcome everyone to the Living Man
online uh church. Today we are going to
be getting into the word of God. you go
ahead and put a one in the chat if you
are ready to open the word of God today.
Uh is going to be a very
important
um and I think a very timely message. Uh
we are going to be getting into the word
of God. This is going to be a study.
This is going to be a study of the word
of God. So, we're going to be going line
upon line, precept upon precept, and uh
we're going to be going very deep into
the scriptures today, but we're going to
illustrate, I'm going to demonstrate
something from the word of God that I
think is absolutely crucial
uh in light of the previous two messages
that um that I shared this past Sabbath
and the Sabbath before. So, with that
said, we're going to go ahead and pray
and uh get into the word of God. Let's
do that now. Heavenly Father,
please Lord, speak through me. Speak to
your people. And Lord, take once again
what is a very complex subject, this
theme of the king of the north and the
king of the south found in Daniel
chapter 11. And Lord, help us to see
some very powerful
truths
from this subject in this message today.
as it ties in with the investigative
judgment. Lord, speak to us is our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Uh please go ahead and uh before I even
begin, I'm going to invite you to hit
the like button, hit the share button,
let people know that this message on the
king of the north and the king of the
south is about to begin. And uh invite
your people. Invite your people. Share
this link. Share. Share. Share. Share.
Share.
Um
we're going to begin, we're going to
begin this message. Uh let's go to the
screen. We're going to begin
in Daniel chapter 8. and we're going to
build step by step to see something
absolutely amazing
regarding this subject. But we're going
to start in Daniel chapter 8. And again,
the title of this message, evangelism,
the king of the north and the king of
the south.
Daniel chapter 8.
Daniel chapter 8 beginning with verse
11, the Bible speaks of this uh little
horn power.
And it describes this little horn power
with these words. It says, "Yeah, he
magnified himself even to the prince of
the host, and by him the daily sacrifice
was taken away, and the place of his
sanctuary was cast down.
And a host was given him against the
daily sacrifice by reason of
transgression,
and it cast down the truth to the
ground, and it practiced and prospered."
Then I heard one saint speaking, and
another saint said unto that certain
saint which spake, How long shall be the
vision concerning the daily sacrifice
and the transgression of desolation to
give both the sanctuary and the host to
be trotten underfoot.
And he said unto me, unto 2, and 300
days, then shall the sanctuary be
cleansed.
We have learned in previous studies that
the book of Daniel is written in
parallel format.
Meaning the prophecies of Daniel that
are found in Daniel chapter 2, Daniel
chapter 7, Daniel chapter 8, Daniel
chapter 9, and Daniel chapter 11 and 12
parallel. They repeat and enlarge.
In Daniel chapter 8, we we see this
judgment or this cleansing of the
sanctuary and this work that is being
done by the little horn. For the purpose
of our study today,
we want to find the parallel event in
Daniel chapter 11, the last prophetic
chapter of the Bible.
So where in Daniel 11 do we find the
parallel of Daniel chapter 8? Do we find
the event of the little horn and the
casting down of the sanctuary uh and
this and this abomination if you will
um this transgression of desolation.
And so if we go to Daniel chap 11, we
will find the parallel in Daniel 11 and
verse 31.
Note with me, and arms shall stand on
his part, and they shall pollute the
sanctuary of strength, and take away and
shall take away the daily sacrifice, and
they shall place the abomination that
maketh desolate. So, let's pause for a
second
and and let me ask I'm going to ask you
to put a five in the chat if you
understand if you see the parallel
between what we just read in Daniel 8,
this little horn polluting the
sanctuary, taking away the daily, the uh
placing the transgression of desolation,
and Daniel 11:31,
which describes literally the same
event. arms shall stand on his part.
Meaning this little horn will have a
military.
They shall pollute the sanctuary of
strength and take away the daily and
place the abomination that maketh
desolate. All right. Excellent. So, um,
we're on the same page. We're going to
keep reading in Daniel 11. So, Daniel
11:32.
Notice what the text says. And such as
do wickedly against the covenant shall
he corrupt by flatteries. But the people
that do know their God shall be strong
and do exploits.
And they that understand among the
people shall instruct many. Yet they
shall fall by the sword and by flame and
by captivity and by spoil many days.
Okay.
So um note here that in Daniel 11 it
goes on to describe the fact that those
who do wickedly against the covenant
will be corrupted by flatteries. But the
people that do know their God shall be
strong and do exploits. So who would the
people who do know their God, who would
those people be in the context of this
little horn power?
We understand
that according to the Bible, this little
horn power represents the papacy. And
the papacy particularly during the dark
ages. So who would be the people who do
know their God that were strong and
doing exploits? You might say, "Pastor,
that would represent the Protestant
reformers particularly during the dark
ages." And if you said that, you would
be correct. You would be correct. The
text goes on to say that they that
understand among the people shall
instruct many. This is exactly what the
Protestant reformers did. Yet they shall
fall by the sword and by flame and by
captivity and by spoil. This is exactly
what happened with the Protestant
reformers. And the Bible says that this
this would happen for many days. Now I'm
going to ask a question. When or what
are these many days?
How long would this period of many days
be?
Let's let's let's see how many of you
are following along. this many days in
which uh God's people would be would be
persecuted
by the little horn.
We don't need to guess
because in Daniel chapter 7 uh Daniel 7
the Bible says note with me and he shall
speak great words against the most high
and shall
wear out the saints of the most high and
shall think to change times and laws and
they shall be given into his hand until
a time times and the dividing of times.
So we understand we understand that
this
many days
in Daniel 7:25 is explained to us as the
1,260
days, the period of the dark ages. So
what we see in Daniel 11 beginning with
verse 31 is a parallel
of Daniel chapter 8, this little horn
power
casting down the sanctuary,
persecuting the people of the most high.
It's parallel in Daniel 11 begins in
verse 31. And we're seeing this parallel
clearly. We are seeing this 1260day
period clearly. Now I'm going to show
you something that you may not have seen
before. So, let's go back to Daniel 11.
And now we're going to pick up with
verse 34.
Notice with me verse 34. And y'all get
ready to just be blown away. The text
says, "Now when they shall fall, they
shall be hoping with a little help, but
many shall cleave to them with
flatteries.
When they shall fall, let me read it
again. When they shall fall, they shall
be hoping with a little help. That's an
interesting phrase.
When they shall fall, we've just seen in
the previous verse that they would be
persecuted for many days, meaning that
would culminate with 1798, the 12 1,260
days or prophetic years. The next test
text says when they shall fall they
shall be hoping or helped with a little
help.
Why is this significant?
Let's go over to Revelation 12.
Revelation chapter 12 beginning with
verse 14. The Bible says, "And to the
woman, that means the church, were given
two wings of a great eagle, that she
might fly into the wilderness into her
place, where she is nourished for, guess
how long, everybody? A time, times, and
half a time from the face of the
serpent."
Are y'all catching this? This is the
same time period here and the same thing
being described. The woman represents
the church. She is being persecuted by
this power by the serpent, if you will,
for 1,260
years. And then the Bible says, "And the
serpent cast out of his mouth water as a
flood after the woman that he might
cause her to be carried away of the
flood." And now what's that next verse,
y'all?
Is anybody excited yet?
and the earth helped the woman and the
earth opened her mouth and swallowed up
the flood which the dragon cast out of
his mouth. So I want you to see here the
absolutely beautiful parallel
in Daniel 11 beginning with verse 31.
Verse 34
when it specifically talks about they
shall be open with a little help. that
is describing Revelation 12 14-16
where the earth helps the woman
particularly towards the end of this
period of persecution this 1,260
years. If you're with me so far, y'all
go ahead and put a five in the chat.
This is going to be a very deep study,
but it's going to be a very powerful
one. And I just want to make sure that
I'm not losing anybody yet because we're
going to be to be focusing in on Daniel
11.
So, so far we see that in Daniel 11
there is a there is a persecuting power
that does the exact thing that is
described in Daniel chapter 8. Daniel 11
goes on to describe the dark ages. He
would be persecuted. This power or God's
people will be persecuted for many days.
We know that that many days is the 1,260
years. And it says when they shall fall,
that is being persecuted, they will be
hoping with a little help. Oh, that's
Daniel 12. That's the end of the 1260
years. Now, now that we are on the same
page, I'm going to introduce to you
verse 35. So whatever is happening in
verse 35 will be after verse 34 after
1798.
Please note what the text says. Let's go
to the screen.
Daniel 11 and verse 35. Watch this now
y'all. And some of them of understanding
shall fall
to try them
and purge
and to make them white
even to the time of the end because it
is yet for a time appointed. Can y'all
tell me what Daniel 11 and verse 35 is
talking about?
Some of them have understanding. So,
what is understanding?
Understanding means they've got a pretty
good grasp on the scripture. Y'all just
go ahead and put a fire emoji if you
can. I'm not even going to ask for a
number for this one. Y'all go ahead and
put a fire emoji if you can. If you see
Daniel 11:35
in a way that you may have never seen
before,
some of them have understanding.
They've got understanding.
They have understanding.
They understand the scriptures.
Some of them of understanding shall
fall.
This is not a a permanent fall. It is a
fall to try them, to test them. Some
kind of test is supposed to happen after
1798, after the many days. Something
that's going to try them and also
involves purging,
cleansing, h to make them white, h even
to the time of the end.
Wow.
Y'all come back to the screen for a
minute.
Can can you think of any event that
would have taken place after 1798
that would involve
people who gained an understanding of
the word of God being tried being tested
to purge
to separate
those who claim to serve God from those
who really serve
also people having to deal with purging,
cleansing. H remember we're talking
about the parallel of Daniel chapter 8.
Remember that.
Remember, in fact, it is quite
interesting that if you were to go to
Revelation 3:9,
where the Bible is speaking about the
the Philadelphiaian church, the
Philadelphiaian church, which
prophetically speaking points to the
great disappointment, notice what
Revelation 3:9 says. Says, "Behold, I
will make them of the synagogue of
Satan, which say they are Jews and are
not, but do lie. I will make them to
come and worship before thy feet and to
know that I have loved thee because thou
has kept the word of my patience. I will
also keep thee from the hour of
temptation which shall come upon the
world to try them. What did Daniel 11:35
say? To try them
to try them that dwell upon the earth.
Wow.
Daniel 11:35 everyone is a reference
to the beginning of the judgment.
It is a reference to the very events
that occur at the end of the 2300 day
prophecy which would make sense because
if Daniel 11 parallels Daniel 8, then we
can expect to see the same thing but in
more detail. Y'all put a one in the chat
if you're following with me so far. In
fact, in fact, it is interesting to note
that in Daniel chapter 7, right after
verse 25, which talks about the 1,260
years, in the very next verse,
let's go back to the screen.
In the very next verse, it says, "But
the judgment shall sit, and they shall
take away his dominion, the little horn,
to consume and to destroy it unto the
end." Unto the time of the end. Come on,
y'all. Come on. Daniel 11:35. and some
of them of understanding shall fall to
try them and to purge them and to make
them white even to the time of the end.
Now hold on, hold on.
I I
want you to follow this. I want you to
check this out.
Daniel 8:13 and 14. Then I heard one
saint speaking, and another saint said
unto that certain saint which speak,
"How long shall be the vision concerning
the daily sacrifice and the
transgression of desolation to give both
the sanctuary and the host to be trodden
underfoot? And he said unto me, unto
2,300 days, then shall the sanctuary be
cleansed." I want you to understand that
the cleansing of the sanctuary parallels
the purging
of God's people.
Are y'all with me so far?
Are you following?
Y'all put a one in the chat.
Put a one in the chat if you are
following the process so far.
So now
I want you to note I want you to note
how in Daniel 8:E1 17 right after it
describes the the cleansing of the
sanctuary it then says for at the time
of the end shall the vision be which
again parallel parallels Daniel 11:35
because it is yet for a time appointed
even to the time of the end. I just want
you to see and follow the parallel.
I want you to note
what Albert Barnes,
Adam Clark, I'm sorry. Um,
no, we're going to do uh Albert Barnes
first. I want you to know what Albert
Barnes had to say on this particular
verse. Are y'all ready?
So Albert Barnes in commenting on and
some of them of understanding shall fall
says some of them who have a correct
understanding of religion and who have
joined the army from pure motives. The
idea seems to be that on some occasion
they would meet with temporary def with
a temporary defeat. Y'all,
you guys,
this is Albert Barn speaking.
And some of them of understanding shall
fall. And his comment is, some of those
who have a correct understanding of
religion and who have joined the army
from pure motives. The idea seems to be
that on some occasion
they would meet with a temporary defeat
in order that the sincerity of the
others might be tested or that it might
be seen who adhered to the cause from
principle and who from selfish purposes.
If they should not always be successful,
if they should be temporarily defeated.
If some of the most eminent among them
should fall among the slain, and if the
cause should at any time look dark, this
would serve to try the sincerity of the
remainder of the army, and would be
likely to thin it off of those who had
joined it only from mercenary motives.
Are y'all catching this?
Now, listen, I see some of you already
kind of jumping ahead. Pastor, what
about verse 40? Isn't that the time of
the end? Isn't 1798 the time of the end?
Yes, y'all listen. 1798 begins the time
of the end, but the time of the end is
an entire period. Daniel 11:40 is making
a reference not only to what happened in
1798, but what happens beyond that. But
what I'm showing you is that from verse
31 onward, this is what begins
the the 1260 years and it culminates
with Daniel 11:4-4.
So, so don't get too confused there.
Just
follow the pattern of thought. Stay with
me where I'm at. And I know some of you
are thinking ahead, wait a minute, what
about this? Let's just follow. I want
you to see something absolutely crucial
here.
So that was Albert Barnes. Albert
Barnes. How about Adam Clark who said
this disputing disputes on certain
points of religion soon agitate the
Christian church. And now having no
outward persecution, they began to
persecute each other. And many excellent
men, men of understanding, fell victim
because they would not embrace erroneous
doctrines
who profess when professed by the state.
But this was permitted to try them and
to purge them to make them white to
bring all to the pure profession
possessing and practice possession and
practice of Christianity.
John Gil says this, "To try their faith,
patience, and other graces, and whether
they would hold fast their profession,
and persevere in the good ways of God,
and to purge and separate them from
others, that were like chaff,
hypocrites, so that they might be
manifest, but both the one and the
other." And these good men appear to be
sincere and upright. Oh, I want you to
just note how how various commentators
say that this verse pointed forward to
some kind of event that would be a
separating event
between those who truly professed
and those who were profess professing
based on
faulty motives.
You guys, I need you to understand how
powerfully this parallels the events of
1844.
Are y'all with me?
How powerfully this points to the events
of 1844.
This is exactly what happens at the end
of the 2300
days.
All right.
Are y'all with me so far? We're just
building a foundation here. We're just
building a foundation here. Daniel 12:9
and 10. Daniel 12:9 and 10. He said, "Go
thy way, Daniel, for the words are
closed up and sealed till the time of
the end. Many shall be purified and made
white and tried. But the wicked shall do
wickedly, and none of the wicked shall
understand." There is a direct parallel
to Kora. A direct parallel. Daniel 12:9,
many shall be purified and made white.
Daniel 11, they shall be purified and
tried. Daniel 8, the cleansing of the
sanctuary. This is all parallel
language. Daniel, sorry, Revelation 7:14
describes the end result of Daniel 11,
uh, Daniel 8, and Daniel 12. These are
they which came out of great tribulation
and have washed their robes and made
them white in the blood of the lamb.
Again,
Malachi 3 2 and 3. But who shall abide
the day of his coming? And who shall
stand when he appearth? For he is like a
refiner's fire and like fuller soap. And
he shall sit as a refiner and purifier
of silver. He shall sit like on a
throne.
And he shall purify the sons of Levi and
purge them as gold and silver that they
may offer an offering
unto righteousness.
All right. Are y'all following so far?
So now let's go back to Daniel 11:32.
Such as do wickedly against the covenant
shall he corrupt by flatteries. But the
people that do know their God shall be
strong and do exploits.
These exploits are to continue until the
end of time.
So what are these exploits?
What what is the situation which calls
for the people of God to do exploits?
Now I want to show you what the word
exploits actually means. The word
exploits in this verse is is is uh
supplied but nonetheless it is correctly
supplied.
So let's talk about exploits for a
second. So the word exploit means to
make full use of and derive benefit from
a resource.
So for example, 500 companies sprang up
to exploit this new technology
or it also means to use a situation or
person in an unfair or selfish way. That
is the company was exploiting a legal
loophole.
Uh accusations that uh that he exploited
a wealthy patient
but also yes Takar you're just getting
that he shall sit. You get that? But
also benefit unfairly from the work of
someone typically by overworking or
underpaying them. Making money does not
always mean exploiting others. So in
general, the word exploit means to take
advantage of a situation. Sometimes it
could be good, sometimes it could be
bad. But listen to me. The Bible says
that God's people will be strong and do
exploits. Meaning according to Daniel
11, there is a situation going on in
which God's people are supposed to
exploit.
Y'all put a put a seven in the chat if
you understand what I just said.
In light of the judgment
and in light of the situation in Daniel
11, God's people are supposed to be
doing exploits.
So the question is, what is the
situation going on in Daniel 11 that
God's people are supposed to use to
their advantage?
Are you with me?
So, so far we've seen Daniel 8 parallels
Daniel chapter 11. In Daniel 8, you have
the explanation of the judgment of God's
people being persecuted, of this little
horn doing his thing, but then those
things being reversed and the sanctuary
will ultimately be cleansed. In Daniel
8, beginning with verse 31, we see the
same thing. And there is repeated
enlarge in Daniel chapter beginning in
Daniel chapter 11 going on all the way
till Daniel chapter 11 verse 45. But
nonetheless what we're seeing is an
unfolding of events
that deal with the little horn and with
judgment. And we've seen so far
specifically with with
God's people
going through this great disappointment
to be tried and ultimately purged as if
a judgment is happening.
Then we see that God's people in this
context are supposed to be doing
exploits. Exploits represents taking
advantage of a situation.
What is the situation in Daniel chapter
11? Let me show you. In Daniel 11, we
are introduced to two characters. Let's
go to Daniel 11:36.
The Bible says, "And the king shall do
according to his will. He shall exalt
himself and magnify himself above every
god and shall speak marvelous things
against the God of gods and shall
prosper till the till the indignation be
accomplished
for that that is determined shall be
done.
This is who Daniel 11
identifies as the king of the north.
This is the very same power as the
little horn in Daniel chapter 8 and
Daniel 7. So remember in Daniel 7, this
power, this little horn magnifies
himself.
You see the same description in Daniel
11:36.
The king of the north is that that horn
that came out of the out of the northern
uh uh out of that rose out of
one of the horns
in Daniel chapter 8.
So remember Daniel chapter 8 we
identified Rome and then papo Rome.
Papo Rome is a king of the north.
The papacy is symbolic of Babylon.
So, so this is all
hopefully not new knowledge to you.
Now, the Bible says in Daniel 11:40,
note with me, Daniel 11:40, at the time
of the end shall the king of the south
push at him. So, who is this king of the
south that pushes against the king of
the north? Well, the king of the south
was symbolic of Egypt.
And out of the four horns that rose out
of out of uh out of uh the Grecian
Empire, uh remember one horn took the
northern hemisphere and the other horn
took the southern hemisphere. the
northern hemisphere um became known as
the Seucid Empire and the southern
hemisphere became known as the Egyptian
Empire or the the they took over the the
territory of Egypt I should say. So, the
king of the north, Babylon, the king of
the south, Egypt, and then when you get
to Revelation chap 11, in Revelation
chapter 11, we're not going to read this
entire thing, but we see this power
rising on the scene, which is identified
as spiritually Egypt.
And according to Bible prophecy and
according to a study on Daniel chapter
11, we see that the event here in which
this power
attacks the two witnesses, meaning the
word of God, the Old Testament and the
New Testament was atheism, right? That
which is against the Bible. So
spiritually speaking on the one hand the
king of the north represents the papacy
apostate Protestantism and all which
claim the Bible claim Jesus but are not
really following. And then the king of
the south would symbolize Egypt which
has come to represent atheism. Who is
God that I should obey him? This is this
is the juiced version of a of a in-depth
study on Daniel chapter 11.
So with this said
now we understand that whatever the
exploits are that God's people are
supposed to be doing the exploits
the situation
in which God's people should be
exploiting
is this battle between the king of the
north and the king of the south. Does
that make sense?
Y'all put a put a five in the chat if
you understood the point that I've been
building up to.
What God's people are supposed to be
taking advantage of, what we're supposed
to be exploiting
for a good purpose is this battle
between
the professed religious
and those who don't claim rel religion
at all. the king of the north and the
king of the south,
Babylon
and
Egypt.
Are you with me?
So, when the text says that they will be
strong and do exploits, we might ask a
question, well, what does it mean in the
context to be strong and do exploits?
And all we got to do is go over to 2
Timothy 2:1 and note what 2 Timothy
chapter 2:1 says. It says, "Thou
therefore be strong,
be strong in the grace that is in Christ
Jesus, and the things that thou hast
heard of me among many witnesses, the
same. Commit thou to faithful men, who
shall be able to teach others also. Thou
therefore endure hardness as a good
soldier of Jesus Christ." Okay. So,
we now see that to be strong
is to
commit
faithful men to teaching and spreading
the gospel. So, when the text says
that these will be strong and do
exploits, oh, it's just another way of
saying they're going to be spreading the
gospel.
They're going to be doing evangelism.
Now, listen, this this sermon is an
in-house sermon. So, so I just saw
someone say, "Well, how did you get King
of the North and how do you get Egypt?
You're spiritualizing." No, no, no. I'm
not I'm just not taking the time right
now to do an actual indepth study to
demonstrate why the little horn is
actually the papacy and the the king of
the south which is described in
Revelation 11 as spiritual Egypt
represents spiritual Egypt and atheism.
We're not doing that today. I might do
that at another time. I've done previous
videos on this. So, just I I'm watching
who's commenting and I want to make sure
that I'm taking into account everyone
who's watching right now. So, for the
for those of you who have never heard
this before, I understand. But know that
know that I'm going somewhere with this
message.
Okay? And I'm not going to fight with
you in the comment either. Okay? So,
we're just gonna I'm gonna move on.
Reach out to me. Email me if you need
to. Okay? For those of you who are like,
"What are you talking about? The king of
the north is the papacy or what are you
talking about? The king of the south is
Egypt." Email me. We'll have a study.
Okay. So, let's move on. So,
let's deal with the king of the north
first.
Let's deal with the king of the north
If God's people are to be exploiting,
taking advantage of a situation,
then it is obvious that if the situation
involves evangelism,
that oh, God must want us to do
something while
or in conjun or in in light of this
battle between the king of the north,
Babylon, and the king of the south,
Egypt.
What does the gospel spreading the
gospel have to do
with this context of Daniel 11?
So, let's go to the screen. Let's deal
with Babylon first.
Jeremiah 24:9, the Bible says, "Behold,
I will send and take all the families of
the of the north, sayeth the Lord, and
Nebuchadnezzar, the king of Babylon, my
servant, and will bring them against
this land." So, I want you to note how
here how Nebuchadnezzar is literally
identified as the king of the north. He
is the king of Babylon. At the end of
time, Babylon is not a literal kingdom.
It is a spiritual entity.
So the king of the north represents
spiritual Babylon. But here in Jeremiah
24:9,
Babylon and the and Nebuchadnezzar are
identified as from the north.
In fact, I don't I didn't have the verse
in front of me, but in in another verse,
Babylon is called the literally called
the king from the north. a king of kings
and lord of lords. That's what the text
literally gives him that title.
And so it says here, "Behold, I will
take of all the families of the north,
say the Lord, and Nebuchadnezzar, the
king of Babylon, my servant." That's an
interesting term,
my servant.
and will bring them against this land
and against the inhabitants thereof and
against all these nations round about
and will utterly destroy them and make
them an astonishment and in hissing and
a perpetual desolation. So we see here
that God is telling uh uh Jerusalem that
Babylon is going to come and capture
them.
We get to Daniel chapter 1. So remember
now Babylon king of the north. Why is
God what does God want us to understand
about evangelism in the context of the
king of the north? Let me show you
Daniel 1 vers1. In the third year of the
reign of Jehoakim, king of Judah, came
Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon, onto
Jerusalem, and besieged it.
And the Lord gave Jehoakim,
king of Judah, into his hand with part
of the vessels of the house of God,
which he carried into the land of
Shinar, to the house of his God, and
brought the vessels into the treasure
house of his God. y'all.
So,
my friend Mondo and I were talking the
other day. I was out in Virginia and and
and
Mando says to me, and the way he put it,
I had already thought this, but the way
he put it, it was just so like, wow.
He was like, "Do you realize
what God is doing here?"
I want y'all to think about this for a
second. Do you realize what God is doing
here? God has put the king of Judah
and the sanctuary into the possession of
Nebuchadnezzar.
Why is he doing that?
Does God
h
Why is God calling Nebuchadnezzar his
servant?
Is God trying to expose Nebuchadnezzar
to the sanctuary?
[Music]
God allows Nebuchadnezzar to get a hold
of the king of Judah.
I want y'all to think please and think
carefully. The king of Judah and the
sanctuary.
Jerusalem. I've called you to be a light
to the world, but y'all are not y'all
are not doing what I've asked you to do.
I need you to be a saving light to the
nations.
All right?
If you don't want to do it the easy way,
then we will do it
the hard way.
I want you to check this out. Check this
out. Uh uh Daniel 1:3. So So watch this
now, beloved. In other words, listen
carefully.
The book of Daniel
as it relates to the kingdom of Babylon
is about God trying to win Babylonians.
Y'all go ahead and put a five in the
chat. The book of the book of Daniel as
it relates to Babylon is about God
seeking
to witness to the Babylonian Empire.
Did y'all catch that just now?
Now, I know you're thinking, "Okay,
pastor, I didn't think about that point,
but I know we're called to I need you to
follow along. I need you to watch this.
Come with me to Daniel chapter 1."
Daniel chapter 1, verse three. And the
king spake unto Ashanaz, the master of
his Unix, that he should bring certain
of the children of Israel, and of the
king's seed, and other princes, children
in whom was no blemish, but
well-favored, and skillful in all
wisdom, and cunning in knowledge, and
understanding signs, and such as had
ability in them to stand in the king's
palace, whom they might teach the
learning in the tongue of the
Calaldanss. Watch this, y'all. Watch
this. Watch this. Watch this. And the
king appointed them. Wait a minute. Wait
a minute. Where's my text? Oh, boy. It's
not there. Here
we go. And the king appointed them a
daily provision of the king's meat and
of the wine which he drank, so
nourishing them for three years, that at
the end thereof they might stand before
the king. And now watch this. Now among
them were the children of Judah, Daniel,
Haniah, Mishael, and Aariah. Listen
y'all. What is God doing?
What is God doing? He is sending
the spirit of prophecy
into the Babylonian Empire.
He's given them the king of Judah.
He's given them the sanctuary. And he's
given them a prophet.
Why?
What can we learn from Daniel's
interaction in Babylon?
But that God loved Nebuchadnezzar.
Your goal
is to witness. Now watch this. Let let's
go back to the screen. Daniel 1:8. But
Daniel purposed in his heart that he
would not defile himself with the
portion of the king's meat, nor with the
wine which he drank. Therefore, he
requested of the prince of the Unix that
he might not defile himself. Now, God
had brought Daniel into favor and tender
love with the prince of the Unix. Please
understand this. Daniel is tested.
Daniel, before I'm sending you into
Babylon to do a work for me, to do
exploits. To do exploits. Let me say it
again. To do exploits, Daniel, I got to
check your character.
Daniel is tested in character. Note what
the text says.
He's tested in character. And and the
Bible says, "The prince of the unic said
unto Daniel, I fear the Lord my king,
who has appointed your meat and your
drink. For why should he see your faces
like worse liking than the children
which are of your sort, and then you
shall make me endanger my heart, my head
to the king." Then said Daniel to Melar,
whom the prince of the Unix had set over
Daniel, Haniah, Michelle, Mishael, and
Aariah, prove thy servants, I beseech
thee 10 days, and you know the deal,
right? They are proved 10 days, and at
the end of the 10 days, they are found
to be greater. They are found to be
greater.
Y'all, a bomb is coming.
Please
follow this carefully, y'all. Something
absolutely mindblowing is coming.
So, watch what happens. Daniel is proven
faithful. And then in Daniel chapter 2,
watch this. In the second year of the
reign of Nebuchadnezzar, Nebuchadnezzar
dreamed dreams wherewith his spirit was
troubled, and his sleep break from him.
Then the king commanded to call the
magicians and the astrologers and the
sorcerers and the calaldians for tow the
king his dream. So they came and stood
before the king
and and the king said unto them, I have
dreamed the dream and the spirit and my
spirit was troubled to know the dream.
Then spayed the Caldanss to the king and
Serak, oh king, live forever. Tell thy
servants the dream and we will show the
interpretation. The king answered and
said unto Calaldians, the thing is gone
from me. And if you will not make known
unto me the dream, the interpretation
thereof, you shall be cut in pieces and
your houses shall be made a dungill. So
let me ask a question.
Does God give the king of Nebuchadnezzar
a dream? Yes or no?
And you might then ask a question, why
is God giving the king of Nebuchadnezzar
a dream? Is it because he want um the
king of Nebuchadnezzar? Is it because he
wants the king of Babylon to be saved?
What do y'all think?
Did God want the king of Babylon to
humble his heart to be saved? Yes, he
did. Did God want Babylonians to be
saved? Yes, he did. And what is God
doing? God sends the king a dream. How
many of you would like God to send you a
dream?
You think, man, Nebuchadnezzar was a
heathen king.
God gave the king a dream. You guys,
that is a powerful witness to God, what
God's ideal, what he wants for people
who are in Babylon today. God is trying
to show them the future
because they don't understand it.
They don't understand prophecy.
They're thinking about it, but they
don't understand it.
And so, and so, uh, uh, Daniel
is asked, Daniel asked, "Give me time
and I will make known the known the
dream." And then Daniel prays to God,
"The interpretation of the dream is
given him. Nobody else can understand
the interpretation. Only Daniel." And
now notice what Daniel chapter 28 and 29
says. But there is a God in heaven that
revealth the secrets and maketh known to
the king Nebuchadnezzar what shall be in
the latter days. Thy dream and the
visions of thy head upon thy bed are
these. As for thee, O king, thy thoughts
came into thy mind upon thy bed, what
should come to pass hereafter, and he
that revealth secret secrets maketh
known to thee what shall come to pass.
Listen to me, you guys.
What was the king of Babylon thinking?
He was thinking about the future.
He was thinking about what's to come.
Can I tell you what's on the mind of
those in spiritual Babylon?
Y'all tell me what is on the mind of
those in spiritual Babylon? What is on
the mind of those who want to make
Babylon great? What is in the mind of
I'm sorry, not Babylon great. What is in
the mind
of those who want to make Babylon great
again? What is in the mind of those who
see nationalism? They are Christians and
they they they believe that that America
uh uh is the head, should be the head,
and we will be the glorious land of will
be the last hope of this world. What is
on their minds, beloved? They're
genuinely thinking about the future, but
they don't understand it. Are y'all with
me?
And what God needs is Daniel's
to explain the prophecies.
God is working. Listen to me y'all. God
is working
with people in Babylon, but he also
needs his own people
to be there and show up for duty.
Now, now watch this. After Daniel
explains the dream to Nebuchadnezzar, I
want you to notice the response. Then
the king Nebuchadnezzar fell upon his
face and worshiped Daniel. You guys, we
could stop the sermon right here, but we
are not going to because this is only
the surface. This is only the surface.
Please read that again. the king of
Babylon, the king of the north.
Now, don't think I'm saying what you
might think, oh, is this what he's
alluding to? No. The ultimate king of
the north, who is Satan, will never bow
to Jesus. He will only when it's too
late.
But I what I want you to see, beloved,
is that God has hope for people in
Babylon. God has love for people in
Babylon. And when the text says
Nebuchadnezzar fell upon his face and
worshiped Daniel and commanded that they
should offer an oblation and sweet
orders unto him, the king said unto
Daniel, "Of a truth it is that your God
is a God of gods, and a Lord of kings,
and a revealer of secrets. Seeest thou
could read, reveal, thou could reveal
the secrets." Then the king made Daniel
a great man and gave him many great
gifts and made him ruler over the whole
province of Babylon. Y'all catch that?
Made him ruler over the whole province
of Babylon. May I suggest to you that
God is trying to put his people in a
place where they will have
they will have inroads
to minister to those in Babylon.
Now, now watch this, you guys.
This same king in Daniel 3 makes an
image of all gold.
He's heard the vision, but he's like,
"Yeah, I don't think my kingdom's going
to fall." So, he makes an image of all
gold. And what I want to share with you,
beloved, is that Daniel doesn't bow to
the vision. Daniel doesn't say, "Yay,
make Babylon great again.
I'm with you, king." He doesn't do that.
And what Nebuchadnezzar does is he calls
together. Don't get mad at me y'all.
Just listen. He calls together a parade
to celebrate
Babylon.
Babylon's might, Babylon's military,
Babylon's power. Is this not great
Babylon that I have built? and and
Daniel being true being a true friend to
Nebuchadnezzar.
Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego who are
in the story being a true witness to
Nebuchadnezzar don't go along with,
"Yay, make Babylon great again." No, no,
no, no, no, no. They're going to stand
for principle and truth and say, "No,
we're not down with you with this vision
because this vision is not God's vision.
God needs Daniels, Shadrach, Meshaches,
and Abedneles who will stand
and be true witnesses
to those in Babylon. I'm not bowing to
your false image of what you think is
going to happen in the future. No, no,
no, no. There is prophecy that states
that this, this, this, and this is going
to happen. And so, no, I will not bow
before your golden image, and I will not
join in with your parade. I'm not
bowing.
In Daniel chapter 4, watch this. In
Daniel chapter 4, after Nebuchadnezzar
reaches the height of pride, he is
humbled. And read these words, beloved,
and read them carefully. Nebuchadnezzar
the king unto all people, nations, and
languages. Sounds like Revelation
chapter 14, doesn't it? How was
Nebuchadnezzar joining in to proclaim a
message to people, all peoples, nation,
nations, and languages that dwell on the
earth? Peace be unto you.
I thought it good to show the signs and
wonders that the high God has wrought
toward me. How great are his signs and
how mighty are his wonders. His kingdom
is an everlasting kingdom and his
dominion is from generation to
generation. And he goes on and concludes
with this. Now I Nebuchadnezzar praise
and extol and honor the king of heaven.
All whose works are truth and his ways
judgment and those that walk in pride
he's able to obey. Do you see this? The
king of Babylon
converts
to become a follower of the God of
heaven.
Wow.
Now beloved, this lets us know something
that in Babylon there are people who are
ripe for conversion.
People in high places, people in low
places. We should be trying to win all
of them. However, there's a second king
in Babylon, isn't there? Yeah, there's a
second king. Let's go to Daniel chapter
5. Daniel chapter 5
and and and verse one. Belshazar the
king made a great feast to a thousand of
his lords and drank wine before the l
before the thousand. Belshazar while he
tasted the wine commanded to bring the
gold and the silver vessels which his
father Nebuchadnezzar had taken out of
the temple which was in Jerusalem that
the king and his princes his wives and
his concubines might drink therein. And
y'all remember the story, right? There's
a writing on the wall. And then that
Daniel comes in and and and Daniel tells
him, he says, "Listen, your father
converted and you knew better."
He He understood and was converted. You
know this. And you still did what you
did.
You still blasphemed God.
And he ends with these words. Look at
the screen. Daniel 5, your kingdom is
numbered and finished. Your weight in
the balances. Your kingdom is divided
and given to the Mes and the Persians.
Now, who led the Mes and the Persians?
It was Cyrus.
The Mes and the Persians are from the
east and the north.
I want you to understand that Cyrus is a
type of Jesus. This is pretty well-known
knowledge.
Cyrus is a type of Jesus. Babylon falls
to a person who is a type of Jesus.
So
what do we learn so far? We see that God
witnessed to Babylon. That's what Daniel
is talking about. God was a witness to
Babylon.
God witnessed to Babylon through he
utilized their desire to know the future
and he said, "Hey, listen. I know you
want to know the future. Let me come in
and show you what the Bible actually
says. Let me come in and show you who
this king of the north actually is. Let
me come in and show you what this 1260
actually means. Let me come in and show
you what this little horn actually is
going to do. Let me come in and show you
about this beast that has horns like a
lamb and speaks as a dragon." and be
willing to say that to the face of
apostate Protestantism. To be willing to
say that to the face of the papacy and
say, "Listen, this is not a dig against
you personally, but I need to show you
that this is what prophecy is. These are
the exploits. God wants us to take
advantage
of this war
by winning those who are of the king of
the north."
Are y'all with me so far?
All right. Are y'all ready for the bomb?
Put a five in the chat if you're ready
for the bomb. Put a five in the chat if
you're ready for the bomb. Cuz
everything I shared up to now is just
was just a buildup, y'all. Y'all ready
for this?
Y'all ready?
What about Egypt?
How does God feel about Egypt, the king
of the south?
So when we think about Egypt,
we typically think about Moses,
right? Pharaoh, who would be considered
the king, right, of Egypt, the king of
the south, Pharaoh.
And we think of the whole Moses Israel
thing. But I'm going to take y'all
someplace else.
Let's go to Genesis chapter 39.
And Daniel
was brought down to Babylon.
H.
You're probably saying, "Pastor, you're
reading that wrong.
I know.
I just want you to note the parallel.
And Daniel was brought down to Babylon.
Now the text does not say Daniel was
brought down to Babylon. The text says
Joseph was brought down to Egypt. So
please note then Daniel is brought to
Babylon while Joseph was brought to
Egypt. Daniel was brought to Babylon,
king of the north. Joseph was brought to
Egypt, king of the south. And Joseph was
brought down to Egypt, and Piper and an
officer of Pharaoh, captain of the
guard, an Egyptian, brought him of the
hands of the Israelites, which had
brought him down, which had brought him
down thither. Come on, y'all. And the
Lord was with Joseph, and he was a
prosperous man, and he was made, and he
was in the house of his master, the
Egyptian. Come on, let's keep reading.
And his master saw that the Lord was
with him and that the Lord made all that
he did to prosper in his hand. H wow.
And Joseph found grace in the sight in
his sight and served him. And he made
him overseer of his house and all that
he had put into his hands. Let's keep
going. And it came to pass that from
time to time he made him or from that
time he made him overseer in his house
over all that he had. And the Lord
blessed the Egyptians house for Joseph's
sake. And the blessing of the Lord was
upon all that he had in the house and in
the field. And he left all that he had
in Joseph's hand. And he knew ought not
and he knew not ought he had save the
bread which he did eat. And Joseph was a
goodly person and well favored. Are
y'all following this? Are y'all
following this? Come on y'all. Come on.
And it came to pass after these things
that they tried Daniel
that they put these unclean foods before
Daniel.
Oh, my bad. I'm thinking about Babylon.
And it came to pass after these things
that his master's wife cast her eyes
upon Joseph and said, "Lie with me." But
he refused and said unto his master's
wife, "Behold, my master walked not what
is with me in the house, and he has
committed all that he is to my hand.
There is none greater in this house than
I, neither has he kept back anything
from me, but thee, because thou art his
wife, how can I do this great wickedness
and sin against God?" Do y'all see this?
Just like Daniel was test like Daniel
was brought down to Babylon, king of the
north, Joseph was brought down to Egypt,
king of the south. Just as Daniel has
been tested to check his character, king
of the king of the north, Babylon. So,
Joseph is being tested for his
character.
Y'all put a five in the chat, y'all.
Come on.
Now watch this y'all. Watch this. Are
you ready? Are you ready?
And it came to pass at the end of two
full years that Pharaoh had a dream.
Let's pray. Let's close the sermon.
Let's say amen. Let's go. Let's go home.
We We We just We just stop. We can stop
right here, y'all.
Come back. Come back for a moment.
Please come back for a moment.
Come here. Let Let's take that slide
down for a second.
You guys,
you guys.
Nebuchadnezzar,
king of Babylon, has a dream.
He's not gonna get the dream. So God
God is going to provide a man who's
going to do exploits,
help the king of Babylon understand
according to his concerns. Cuz in the
north, their concerns were the future
and and and what's going to happen to
the kingdom. And and that was their
concerns.
Now we see Joseph
being sent to Egypt, a prisoner, just
like Daniel was in Babylon, a prisoner.
Daniel 11, Daniel 11, beloved, is about
this battle between the king of the
north and the king of the south while
God's people are are in the center. And
God says, "My people, I need you to do
exploits."
What are those exploits, Lord? I need
you. There are people in Babylon that I
need you to win. And there are people in
Egypt, the king of the south, that I
need you to win. But they both require
different approaches
because they have different concerns and
different cares.
Legitimate concerns and legitimate
cares.
But they're both missing the big
picture.
Come back. Let's go back to the screen.
Y'all need to see this, y'all. Daniel
Genesis chapter 41. And it came to pass
at the end of two full years that
Pharaoh dreamed, and behold, he stood by
the river. And behold, there came up of
the river seven well-favored kind and
flat and fat-fledged, and they fed in
the meadow. And behold, seven other kind
came up after them out of the river,
ill-favored and lean-fledged, and stood
by the other kind upon the brink of the
river.
And they and the ill-favored lean flesh
kind did eat up the seven well-favored
kind. And so Pharaoh awoke, and he slept
and dreamed the second time. And behold,
seven ears of corn came up on the stalk,
ranking good. And behold, seven thin
ears blasted up with the east wind
sprung up after them. And the seven thin
ears devoured the seven rank and full
ears. And Pharaoh awoke, and behold, it
was a dream. And it came to pass in the
morning that his spirit was troubled.
Just like Nebuchadnezzar's spirit was
troubled. I need y'all to understand,
beloved, that God is troubling those who
are part of the kingdom of the south.
And God is troubling those who are part
of the kingdom of the north. And he's
troubling them with different things,
different thoughts. But what God needs
most of all, beloved, is his people who
are supposed to be strong and doing
exploits to be ready and prepared and
know how do I minister to those who are
of the kingdom of the south and how do I
minister to those who are of the kingdom
of the north? But beloved, if God's
people are not strong and are not doing
exploits, but instead infighting against
each other, oh, now you get the picture.
Now you get the picture. Listen to me.
It came to pass in the morning that his
spirit was troubled and he sent and
called for all the magicians of Egypt.
Y'all might be thinking we are reading
Daniel chapter 2 right now, but we are
not reading Daniel chapter 2. We are not
talking about the king of the north
right now. We are talking about the king
of the south.
You might think this is Daniel chapter
2, but no, this is Genesis chapter 41.
And the text says, "And all the wise men
thereof, and Pharaoh told them his
dream, but there was none that could
interpret them unto Pharaoh." Come on,
somebody. Latana is absolutely right.
Come on, somebody.
What in the world? What in the world?
How do you have the king of Babylon and
the king so to speak of Egypt, the
Pharaoh of Egypt, and God is ministering
to them both?
He's giving them dreams, setting them up
to interact
with those who possess the spirit of
prophecy.
Let's go. Genesis 41:2. And Joseph said
unto Pharaoh, "The dream of Pharaoh is
one." God has showed Pharaoh what he's
about to do. Let me tell you, beloved,
God is showing people in the kingdom of
the south things that are about to
happen. He's showing them, but they
don't quite fully get it. They are
seeing, listen to me, they are seeing
project 2025,
but they don't fully understand the
significance. They are seeing this
merging of church and state, but they
don't quite get it. And they certainly
don't have God in the picture.
Are you following
God is showing the Babylonians one thing
and he's showing the Egyptians something
else, but he's doing it in order to set
up God's people to be able to win both
Nebuchadnezzar's and Pharaohs.
Now, I want you to note, beloved, what
Pharaoh's concern is. So first Joseph
says to Pharaoh, "Listen, behold, there
cometh seven years of great plenty
throughout all the land of Egypt, and
then shall arise after them seven years
of famine, and all the plenty shall be
forgotten in the land of Egypt, and the
famine shall consume the land. And the
plenty shall not be known in the land by
reason of the famine following, for it
shall be very grievous." And for that
the dream was double unto Pharaoh twice.
It is because the thing is established
by God, and God will shortly bring it to
pass. Now watch this. And the thing was
good in the eyes of Pharaoh, and in the
eyes of all his servants. And Pharaoh
said unto his servants, can we find such
a one as this, in a man in whom the
spirit of the God is? And Pharaoh, in
whom the spirit of God is. And Pharaoh
said unto Joseph, for as much as God has
showed thee all this, there is none so
discreet and wise as thou art. Come on,
somebody. Thou shalt be over my house,
and according unto the word, my thy
word, shall all my people be ruled. Only
in the throne will I be greater than
thou. And Pharaoh said unto Joseph,
"See, I have set thee over all the land
of Egypt." Now, come on, y'all. How is f
How is Joseph gonna be set over the land
of Egypt, and Daniel set over the land
of Babylon? Y'all listen to me.
We need Joe Daniels.
We need Dan Fs.
What God's people are the called to be
is a combination
of Joseph and Daniel combined into one.
So that we know how to minister to the
to the king of the south and we know how
to minister to the king of the north.
Please note with me note with me that
that that Pharaoh's concern Genesis
41:55 listen to this. And when all the
land of Egypt was famished, the people
cried to Pharaoh for bread. And Pharaoh
said unto all the Egyptians, "Go unto
Joseph. What he saith to you, do listen
y'all.
Are y'all ready for this?" Pharaoh's
concern
was about the community.
Pharaoh's concern
Do the people have enough to make it
through a famine? Are the people fed
prophecy and combine it with community
service?
That's how you're going to reach the
king of the south.
You can't just ignore the plight of the
people. You can't just ignore racism.
You can't just ignore poverty. You can't
just for the kings of this for the king
for the for the for the for the southern
kingdom you have to address what their
concerns are. And for the northern
kingdom the same thing,
DJs,
JD's, however you want to say it, Joe
Daniels, Dan Fs, however you want to put
it. What God is looking for is a
combination of Joseph and Daniel so that
we are involved in our communities while
not getting rid of prophecy. Because
prophecy is that which brings both
are y'all catching
are y'all catching what I'm saying here?
Are y'all understanding the significance
of what I'm pointing out to you today?
By understanding how northerners think
and understanding how southerners think,
God says, "Meet them where they are."
Pharaoh is evidently is Pharaoh is being
shown about community loss that he's
going to experience. Nebuchadnezzar,
he's thinking about the end of the
world. He's thinking about how is this
all going to end? What's the bigger
picture? And God says, "Listen, for
those on the north, right? For those on
the north, right? Right. For those on
the north, here's how I want you to
bring prophecy to them. For those on the
south, here's how I want you." The three
angels messages must be adapted
to meet northerners where they are and
southerners where they are. And beloved,
what happens is when we jump on the
northerners side and say, "Yeah, those
wicked old southerners," we are missing
the point. And when we jump on the
southern side and say that there's no
hope for the northerners, we're missing
the point. God is calling us to
evangelize, but he's calling us to do it
faithfully.
When you're in the north, don't go along
with the parades of the north, y'all.
When you're in the south, don't go along
with the denials of God.
Come on y'all. When you're in the south,
identify with the famines in the land.
When you're in the south, identify with
the plight of the people. Don't think it
is weakness or don't think it is, oh,
you're just you're just being loving.
And that's what what the God what the
gospel calls. We've got to speak the
truth. No, beloved, listen to me. God
spoke to Pharaoh in his way and and
Nebuchadnezzar in his way.
So let's go back to the screen. Exodus
1:8. Now there were arose a new king
over Egypt. Because remember, just as
there were two kings in Babylon, one
whoa, that king responded, the other Oh,
he didn't respond too well. Guess what?
There were two pharaohs in Egypt.
The first pharaoh, oh man, what a
response. The second, listen, there
arose up a new king over Egypt, a new
king of the south, which knew not
Joseph. And he said unto his people,
"Behold, the people of the children of
Israel are more and mightier than we.
Come on, let us deal wisely with them,
lest they multiply. And it come to pass,
that when there fallth without any war,
they join also to our enemies, and fight
against us, and so get them up out of
the land. Therefore, they did set over
them task masters to afflict them with
their burdens. And they built for
Pharaoh treasure cities, Pitham and
Ramsies. But the more they afflicted
them, the more they multiplied and grew,
and they were grieved because of the
children of Israel. Do y'all see this?
Listen. Listen to the point I'm making
here, y'all.
In Babylon, there are those who are
right for the picking and those who are
not. In Egypt, there are those who are
not. And what God has called us to do is
he has called us to do exploits. To be
able to know how to minister to the king
of the north as well as how to minister
to, you know, come on y'all. When is the
last time you thought about how can we
minister to the king of to the king of
the north? To the kingdom of the north.
How can we minister the kingdom of the
we just look at go oh evil
evil
in both kingdoms
in both kingdoms there are people who
are ready to receive the truth because
God has already been working with them
and the exploits that God's people are
called to do require requires us to have
good character, requires us to be able
to differentiate between right and
wrong. To be able to understand the
principles of the Bible and not go along
with whatever Babylon says, not go along
with whatever Egypt says, but to be able
to understand the concerns of both Egypt
and Babylon and speak to those concerns
with a prophetic voice.
How do we reach Egypt?
Look at Joseph and think about Isaiah
58.
A call to minister to the poor and the
needy and the oppressed. Oh, so pastor,
is that what you've been saying all
these years? That this is ministry to
the south. When you minister in this,
when the south sees that you are
concerned about about their well-being,
that they're going to have ears to
listen because you fed, you you you you
you gave drink when they were thirsty.
You you went into their communities and
formed ministries and ministered to them
on beh on their behalf on the behalf of
the Lord. And yet you also brought you
didn't throw aside prophecy. You brought
it to the table and showed them, listen,
there's a worse famine coming.
And when you went to the right, you
weren't just like, oh man, I love your
golden image and your parades and your
st Whoa. Yes, I'm with you all the way.
No,
you stood firm and said, "I love you."
And because I love you, I'm telling you
the truth.
The devil is out to deceive you. this
image y'all trying to build and this
nationalism. No, I'm telling you because
I love you. I'm standing against this
image like Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abednego stood against that image.
So,
we're almost done, y'all. I need you to
check this out.
I need you to check this out. Let's go
back to the screen.
Let's go back to the screen. We need Joe
Daniels. We need We need Dan FS. Listen
to this. Listen to this. How does the
story of Babylon end? You remember the
story of Babylon ends like this.
Your kingdom is finished,
is fallen,
and given to the Mes and the Persians.
Those were kings from the north and the
east. So interesting that Revelation
16:12 tells us that the way the end time
Babylon falls is that the sixth angel
pours out his vow upon the great river
and the waters there were dried up that
the ways of the kings of the east might
be prepared.
That's interesting.
Who are the kings of the east?
Ultimately, the one leading the kings of
the east is Jesus, the Cyrus of heaven.
Just as a literal Cyrus overthrew
Babylon, literal Babylon, so the
spiritual Cyrus
will overthrow spiritual Babylon. How
did Egypt end? You'll remember Egypt
ended with plagues
and the wicked dying
in a sea.
A Red Sea. Oh, I'm sorry, I mean the Red
Sea.
Did y'all catch this?
The way the king of the north and the
king of the south end are both des both
both descriptions of the second coming
of Jesus.
And so what is it that God is trying to
do? Listen to me y'all.
He's trying to save Babylonians and
Egyptians from coming destruction.
Wait, wait, what
you mean? That's the exploit. Those are
the exploits that God is looking for his
people to do to save people out of the
kingdom of the north and to save them
out of the kingdom of the south
because destruction is coming.
And now I'm about to show you the
investigative judgment in a way that you
may have never heard it before. Luke
21:35
Jesus says this,
"For as a snare it shall come upon all
them that dwell upon the face of the
whole of the whole earth." Watch ye
therefore and pray always that you may
be accounted worthy to escape.
What does it mean to be accounted worthy
to do something? What other word would
you use in the place of accounted
worthy?
That you may be determined worthy
to escape.
that you may be judged worthy to escape.
Do you understand
that the judgment is about judging us
worthy to escape?
The reason why God wants people from the
king of the north and people from the
king of the south to come out of the
king of the north and to come out of the
king of the south and to join Jerusalem.
Israel,
spiritual Israel. Just as Israel is
spiritual, so Babylon is spiritual, so
Egypt is spiritual. The reason why God
is calling them out is because he wants
to judge them worthy to escape. The
investigative judgment is about clearing
is about judging God's people worthy to
escape. You want to be a part of this
judgment. You do not want to be a part
of the great white throne judgment which
takes place at the end of time. So God
is saying, "Get them out
so that I can judge them worthy
to escape."
Two verses left.
And the children of Israel sjoured from
Ramssey's to Suko about 600,000 on foot
that were with him with men that were
men beside children. And a mixed
multitude went up also with them. Do
y'all understand this? A mixed multitude
that God's trying to save a mixed
multitude.
After this, they beheld, and lo, a great
multitude, which no man could number, of
all nations, and kindreds, and people,
and tongues, stood before the throne,
and before the Lamb clothed with white
robes and palms in their hands, and
cried with a loud voice, saying,
"Salvation to our our God, which siteth
upon the throne, and unto the Lamb."
Listen to me, you guys. Listen.
God is looking for a multitude out of
Egypt, and a multitude out of Babylon.
In fact, it's so interesting. Let me go
back one more text. Let me go back one
text I jumped over. I got to read this.
Speaking of this end time king of the
north, he shall enter also into the
glorious land, and many countries shall
be overthrown. But these shall escape
out of his hand, even Edom, Moab, and
the chief of the children of Ammon. Let
me tell you, Edom, Moab, and the chief
of the children of Ammon were these were
nations that were born out of Lot
and and and Esau.
And they would kind of claim to be
connected with God's people, but would
often side with the enemies of God's
people. They would side with Egypt. They
would side with Babylon. And in fact,
and many times they create they they
basically
were confederate with them against
Israel. When the text says that Edom,
Moab, and Ammon will escape this end
time deception, which is what the text
is saying.
this end time king of the north.
It's using in symbolic language the very
same thing that we just saw. They're
going to be people
who were once connected with these false
systems. As Revelation 18 says, come out
of her
my people.
God has people in these fallen systems.
And I think what troubles me the most
is that to a large degree, instead of us
as God's people doing exploits, we're
pulling exploits on each other.
We're creating
we're creating entire
ministries and messages that are
designed
to do exploits on each other.
Exploiting internal conflict.
There's a good exploitation, winning
souls, and a bad exploitation,
crisis, conflict. Ah, in the church. Oh,
yes.
And I believe, beloved, that that is
Satan's way of keeping us occupied
so that we do not win northerners or
southerners.
So as we look at this amazing parallel,
the story of Joseph, the story of
Daniel, what we see is almost a mirror
image of God loving the Egyptian and God
loving the Babylonian so much so that he
sends prophets to them.
He gives them dreams himself, but they
can't understand.
So God says, "I'm going to send you my
Joe Daniels."
But if we're not studying prophecy, if
our characters are shady, if we rejoice
in wickedness and we rejoice in coldness
and we rejoice in callousness and we and
we think that callous things and cold
things are cool and haha, if we think
that and we think that reaching out to
the to the to the to the poor and the
and the oppressed is somehow silly and
somehow a distraction and somehow work
that other people should be doing and
other churches should be doing, we have
missed the point.
If we think all we need to do is preach
prophecy and not minister
to our communities,
we are sorely mistaken.
If we think all we need to do is
minister to our communities and and
forget about prophecy, we don't need it,
we are sorely mistaken.
The two
come together.
We need Daniels and Joseph. Y'all put a
one in the chat. Put a one in the chat
if today you're saying, "Lord, help me.
Help me to be a Joe Daniel.
Help me to be a JD. Help me to be a DJ.
Help me to be a Danf. Help me to help me
to take these two stories and combine
them within myself. Help our church to
take these two stories and combine them
so that we as a church not only
represent Daniel, but also represent
Joseph." And beloved, let me tell you,
there is a tendency in our church to
think that all we need is Daniel. We
don't need Joseph. All we need is to
tell the truth and to preach prophecy.
We don't need to be in communities doing
X, Y, and Z. Let somebody else do that.
We need to be about the three angels
messages. Beloved, the three angels
messages
is for every nation, kindred, tongue,
and people. It's for Egyptians, and it's
for Babylonians.
Y'all put a one in the chat.
Put that one in the chat.
Heavenly Father,
thank you.
Thank you for showing us this amazing
parallel. It is almost a mirror image
of Daniel and Joseph.
One ministering to the king of the
south, one ministering to the king of
the north. Lord, imagine if Daniel, if
the Daniels called the Josephs evil
or woke
because he cared about the community.
Imagine the Joseph's calling the Daniels
uh uh uh uh lunatics because of their
focus of his focus on on on prophecy.
And and Lord, please help us to
understand
that you're trying to call us as a
people
to minister and to know how to reach
people in their different backgrounds
and their different life situations,
Lord.
And Lord, above all,
help us as a people to stop exploiting
things we ought not to be exploiting
and to start exploiting or taking
advantage of and winning souls for Jesus
among those who claim to believe the
truth but don't fully understand it and
those who claim that the Bible is not
true that there is no God help us Lord
to become Joe Daniels
Forgive us
for exploiting one another
while the devil laughs
and teach us Lord to be strong and do
exploits for you. We pray this in Jesus
name. Amen. Amen. May God bless you.
Um we are going to put the uh link to
Mighty Networks into the chat. Um thank
you guys for tuning in. I pray that this
message
um go study this thing. I pray that this
message will impact you, will impact
your church, will impact our church and
may we be about our father's business.
God bless you and um
draw close to Jesus.
Amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]